这次会议正在录制之中。
This meeting is being recorded.
好吧,我们走。 摆 所以我有大约两个小时的时间来经历一吨的东西。
All right. Okay. So I have about two hours to go through a ton of stuff.
这不会是后继的事情 因为我要动作很快
This is not going to be a follow-along thing because I'm going to move pretty fast
有很多东西我需要覆盖。
with a lot of stuff that I need to cover.
但愿录音能让你了解我所做的一切
But hopefully the recording will give you insights into everything that I'm doing.
我要做的第一件事就是开播
The first thing I'm going to do here is turn on screencast.
摆 在我的屏幕左侧,你会看到什么老鼠按钮
Okay. So here on the left side of my screen, you'll see what mouse buttons I'm
点击时,我点击他们, 以及我按什么键, 所以以后当你
clicking as I click them, and also what keys I'm pressing, so that later when you
看视频,你就会知道 我用什么命令来做所有的事情
watch the video, you'll know exactly what commands I'm using to do everything that
当然 希望这样会有所帮助 我现在就告诉你 Blender需要...
I do. Hopefully, that will help. I will tell you right now that Blender requires a
许多键盘快捷键, 这些东西不会是直观的
lot of keyboard shortcuts, and these things are not going to be intuitive to you at
所有,但你会学习他们, 并最终它会成为第二自然。 好吧,我们走。
all, but you'll learn them, and eventually it will become second nature. All right.
因此,让我开始。 如果你不知道我是谁,我叫瑞哥
So with that, let me get started. If you don't know who I am, my name is Rico
康图 我想是2022年毕业的
Contim. I graduated from the Fab Academy program, I think in 2022.
我不记得了 从此教化. 我住在日本镰仓
I don't remember anymore. I've been teaching ever since. I live in Kamakura, Japan.
我有自己的实验室 我刚刚完成一个孩子的课, 他们离开了一个灾区
I run my own lab. I just got done with a kids' class, and they left a disaster area
在那里,我会 清理之后。 但我喜欢和孩子一起工作
over there that I'll have to clean up after this. But I love working with kids.
他们是惊人的。
They are amazing.
我教Blender给四岁半的孩子
I've taught Blender to kids as young as four and a half years old.
有个孩子是恐龙的粉丝 他已经做模特了
There's one kid here who's a huge fan of dinosaurs, and he's already been modeling
Blender身上的恐龙 从他6岁起。 所以,如果他能做到这一点,你可以做到这一点。
dinosaurs on Blender since he was six years old. So if he can do it, you can do it.
这需要一点点的工作来理解它,但
It will require a little bit of work to understand it, but
这不是不可能的。 摆
it's not impossible. Okay.
我首先要给您介绍一下用户界面
With that, I'm going to start off by giving you a tour of the user interface for
布莱德 大多数时候你打开Blender, 它应该看起来什么 -- 是吗?
Blender. Most of the time when you turn on Blender, it should look something-- Am I
共享屏幕? 我不分享屏幕。
sharing screen? I'm not sharing screen.
让我 -- 不
Let me- No
开始做吧
... go ahead and start doing that.
好吧,我们走。 我想我现在分享屏幕。
All right. I think I'm sharing screen now.
当你开始Blender时,你经常看到一个界面,它看起来
Most of the time when you start Blender, you'd see an interface that looks
像这样 让我用我的新工具 来告诉你
something like this. And let me walk you through it using my new fancy tool here
在那里我可以做笔记。 所以我要你们注意的是...
where I can annotate. So what I want you to pay attention to is that there are
其实只是几扇窗户 好吧,这样吧
actually just a few windows. Okay, so
这里有个巨大的窗户 摆
you've got this giant window here. Okay.
我要叫这个,
I'm going to call this one,
一个,你有一个侧窗。 让我看看。 哦,孩子,这行不通的。
one, and you've got a side window. Let me see. Oh, boy, this is not going to work.
我的注解是行不通的。 好吧,所以让我离开这里。
My annotation is not going to work. Okay, so let me get out of this.
你有一个巨大的窗口, 它的名字是3D Viewport。
You've got this big giant window, and its name is the 3D Viewport.
这就是你所有模特的出现地点
And this is where all of your modeling will occur.
每次你操纵某个东西,它就会在这里出现.
Every time you manipulate something, this is where it's going to show up.
右上角是另一扇窗户,叫做"轮廓"
On the upper right-hand corner is another window here called the Outliner.
提纲就像... 如果使用Windows,则是一个Windows Explorer.
And the Outliner is like the-- If you use Windows, it's a Windows Explorer.
如果你用Mac,那它叫什么来着?
If you use a Mac, what is it called on a Mac?
我不知道,文件经理,什么的
I don't know, File Manager or whatever it is.
它基本上列出了你当前文件中的所有内容
It basically lists absolutely everything that is in your current file.
所以,你可能不能读它, 但上面写着相机,立方体,和光。
So you probably can't read it, but it says here Camera, Cube, and Light.
因此,在我的场景 现在,有三个物体。
So in my scene right now, there are three objects.
我有立方体,你注意到 当我点击它, 它突出它过在
I've got the cube, and you notice when I click on it, it highlights it over on the
右手边也一样。 我这里有一个灯光,这是一个灯泡,然后
right-hand side as well. I've got a light here, which is a light bulb, and then
这里有台摄像机 好吗? 所以这绝对列出了你拥有的一切
over here I have a camera. Okay? So this lists absolutely everything that you have
在你的场景。 例如,如果我添加另一个对象, 如果我在此复制此对象
in your scene. If I add another object, for instance, if I copy this object here
我把它放在那里, 现在我有两个立方体。 我有魔方和魔方一号 好吗?
and I put it over there, now I have two cubes. I have Cube and Cube 1. All right?
所以,如果你需要知道,是的, 这将拥有你需要的一切。
So if you need to know, yeah, this will have everything that you need.
好吧,我们走。 然后右下方是属性菜单。
All right. And then over on the lower right-hand side is the Properties menu.
这是Blender最强大的窗口
And this is the most powerful window within Blender here.
如果我点击立方体,你就会看到,有几个图标,也许12个,12个
If I click on the cube, you see that there are several icons, maybe 12, a dozen
图标,每个图标都是Blender某些方面的属性设置。
icons here, and each one of them are property settings for some aspect of Blender.
还有
And there
你记不得太多 但我要你注意的是
are too many for you to remember, but the ones I want you to pay attention to are,
这里有一个看起来像 DSLR摄像机的背面, 我要尝试
there's one here that looks like the back of a DSLR camera, and I'm going to try to
画在这里。
draw it here.
摆 它看起来像一个德国航天中心。
Okay. And it looks like this, a DSLR.
类似这样的东西, oops, 按钮像这样。 好吗? DSLR相机的后部.
Something like this with, oops, buttons like this. Okay? The back of a DSLR camera.
这是您的 Render 属性菜单 。 好吗? 所以请注意这一点。
This is your Render Properties menu. Okay? So please pay attention to that.
下面是一台看起来像打印机的。
And then below that is one that looks like a printer.
摆 我不知道你们有没有Blender开着 但看起来像是
Okay. I don't know if any of you have Blender open, but it looks something like
这个
this.
好吧,这是你的输出属性菜单。
Okay, and this is your Output Properties menu.
我们最终会处理的
We'll be eventually working with that.
然后跳过几个,你看到一个看起来像水滴。
And then you skip a few down, you see one that looks like a water droplet.
那个是你的场景。 好,再来一次
That one is your scene. So, okay, one more again.
DSLR是您的渲染菜单,打印机是您的输出菜单,
DSLR is your Render menu, the printer is your Output menu, the
水滴是你的场景菜单。 我参加场景菜单的唯一原因是
water droplet is your Scene menu. The only reason I ever go to the Scene menu is to
设置我的单位, 像我想工作什么?
set my units, like what do I want to work on?
你会看到这里有一个小分队叫单位, 这就是我定义的地方
You'll see here there's a subsection called Units, and here's where I define
无论我想工作 在米或厘米或什么。
whether I want to be working in meters or centimeters or whatever.
默认为米. 就今天而言,我打算就这样离开
The default is meters. And for today, I'm just going to leave it as is.
再跳下来几下。 到目前为止 Blender的魔法就是这个工具 就是那个
Skip down a couple more. By far, the magic of Blender is this tool, the one that
看起来像蓝色扳手 蓝色扳手图标是修饰者图标,我们将
looks like a blue wrench. Blue wrench icon is the Modifier icon, and we'll be
回到这一个。 因此,这是一种方法 取几何 在Blender并给予它
going back to this one. So this is a way to take geometry in Blender and give it
按钮按下时的额外特殊功能。
extra special features at the push of a button.
所以,例如,我要去 添加修改器,生成子分区
So, for instance, I'm going to go to Add Modifier, Generate Subdivision
表面,我的立方体会变成这样
Surface, and my cube is going to change into this.
所以我把立方体的六面体 分成四面体
So I took each one of the six faces of the cube, and I subdivided it into four
6个面孔 现在我在这个立方体上有12个面孔。
faces per the original six faces. So I now have 12 faces on this cube.
你需要知道 修饰剂是无损的,意思是
And what you need to know about modifiers is that it's non-destructive, meaning
这是一个预览 如果我应用这个修饰符 它会是什么样子。
it's a preview of what it would look like if I applied this modifier.
但如果我决定用这个X标记删除这个修饰符
But if I decide to delete this modifier with this X mark here, the
操纵,几何的修改消失.
manipulations, the modification to the geometry disappears.
因此,这是一个预览 它会对你的物体做什么 直到你真正锁定它
So it's a way to preview what it will do to your object until you actually lock it
进去 跳过一堆,一路到底,你看到一个红色的检查球。
in. Skip a bunch more, all the way to the bottom, you see a red checker ball.
红色检查球是应用材料的地方.
Red checker ball is where you apply the materials.
现在,这个立方体
Right now, this cube has
得到了默认的白色颜色。 所以在这里,如果你想将颜色改为红色,如果
got the default white color. So here, if you want to change the color to red, if
你想让它变成金属
you want to make it metallic
或类似的东西, 这就是你会做到这一点。
or something like that, that's where you would do it.
这就是材料方面。 好吗?
So this is the materials aspect. Okay?
我以后会更详细地描述这一切
I'll cover all of that in greater detail later on.
摆
Okay.
屏幕广播的字母有点太大了
Screencast letters are a little bit too big.
让我稍微换一下
Let me change that down a bit.
你想开始录音吗? 我以为我做到了。 是吗?
Would you like to start the recording? I thought I did. Did I not?
我不知道. 对
I don't know. I am
没有...
not...
对 我以为我做到了。 摆 我看得出来
Yeah. I thought I did. Okay. I can see it.
好吧,我们走。
All right.
最后,这里最下面的那个, 我要把这个叫做辅助
And then lastly, the one at the bottom here, I'm going to call this the auxiliary
窗口
window
因为你可以把它变成任何东西。
because you can change it to anything.
目前,它是时间轴功能,这意味着它被用于动画.
Currently, it is the timeline functionality, which means it's used for animation.
只是想告诉你,这四个窗口中的每一个都可以改为
And just to let you know, every single one of these four windows can be changed to
随便你 在左上角有点
anything you want. On the upper left-hand corner is a little
图标。 如果你点击它, 它会给你选择 绝对的一切
icon. If you click on that, it'll give you options of absolutely everything that
你可以把窗户打开 例如,如果我想要第二个3D视图端口,我可以
you could turn that window into. For example, if I want a second 3D viewport, I can
去那里选择3D Viewport, 现在我有了第二个窗口,可以给我看
go there and select 3D Viewport, and now I have a second window that will show me
我和哪个模特儿一起工作,好吗?
what model I'm working with, okay?
暂时,我要把它留在时间线上,我会做到的
For the time being, I'm going to leave it on timeline, and I'm going to make it
小一点,让我看得见
smaller so that I can see
我这里的大窗户。 有问题吗?
my big window here. Any questions so far?
因此,四个大的主窗口: 3D Viewport, 大纲, 属性,
So four big main windows: 3D Viewport, Outliner, Properties,
和辅佐。 在属性菜单中,您想要聚焦于
and Auxiliary. And in the Properties menu, you want to focus on the back of
DSLR,即Render,打印机,即输出,
DSLR, which is Render, the printer, which is Output,
水滴,即单位,蓝色扳手图标,即修改器,以及
the water droplet, which is Units, the blue wrench icon, which is Modifier, and
红色检查球,即材料。 好吗?
the red checker ball, which is Materials. All right?
犹如驾车. 你车上有很多事情可以做
It's like driving a car. There are lots and lots of things you can do in your car,
但首先你需要学习的是方向盘, 气体和刹车,然后转
but the first thing you need to learn is steering wheel, gas and brake, and turn
信号 除此之外,你以后能想出的一切。 好吗? 摆
signal. Beyond that, everything else you can figure out later. Okay? Okay.
因此,让我们回到 3D 属性窗口,这里的视图窗口。
So with that, let's go back to the 3D properties window, the viewport window here.
还有几件事你需要看看
A couple of other things you need to see.
右上角,你可以看到四个不同的球
Upper right-hand corner, you see four balls of different
设计。 左边最远的那个会转弯的是
designs. The farthest one on the left will turn is the
线框视图. 这是您的视图模式
wireframe view. These are the view modes for your
几何经. 从钢丝架到坚固的视野
geometry. And it goes from wireframe to solid view, to
完成预览 完成预览 。 大部分时间,当你
render preview, to full render. And for the most part, when you're
建模对象时,您想要保持线框模式或固态视图。
modeling your objects, you want to stay in either wireframe mode or solid view.
这是你电脑上最不需要的
These are the least computationally demanding on your computer.
当你移动到预览 或完全渲染的东西, 它会要求
As you move to render preview or the fully rendered thing, it's going to demand
更多来自你的电脑,你的GPU, 如果你碰巧有一个薄弱的计算机,这个
more from your PC, from your GPU, and if you happen to have a weak computer, this
就是你的电脑会崩溃
is what's going to crash your computer.
所以,留在钢丝架上或坚固的视野上做你的模型。
So stay on the wireframe or the solid view to do your modeling.
还有一件事我要你注意 在左边,你看
Another thing I want you to pay attention to is over here on the left, you see a
窗口名为对象模式。 这是
window called Object Mode. This is the
小学
primary
几何操纵模式是对象模式.
geometry manipulation mode is Object Mode.
在"对象模式"中,你会 与,我要说,
And in Object Mode, you're going to be working with the, I'm going to say, the
你的几何学的宏观转变, 意思是大的东西。
macro transformations of your geometry, meaning the big things.
你会让它变大或变小, 你会移动它,或者
You're going to make it bigger or smaller, you're going to move it around, or
你将旋转它。 你不会调整好的
you're going to rotate it. You're not going to be adjusting fine features.
所以大局操纵你的模式。
So the big picture manipulations of your mode.
而且,我们现在在对象模式, 我们将改变这个以后, 但我只是
Also, we're in Object Mode now, and we're going to change that later, but I just
想要您知道模式调整在哪里 。
want you to be aware where the mode adjustments are.
除此之外,
Other than that,
我们要开始在这个窗口进行导航。
we're going to start doing some navigation in this window.
所以,这是我要求你有一个三键鼠标, 因为你可以做到这一点。
So this is where I ask you to have a three-button mouse, because you can do this
有轨迹垫 我不太晓得
with a track pad. I don't quite know.
我认为这就像一个手指,两个手指, 所有这些其他操纵,我
I think it's like one finger, two fingers, all these other manipulations, which I
不太清楚,但是如果你谷歌,你也许可以做到这一点。
don't quite know, but if you Google it, you can probably do it.
就个人而言,因为我想让事情得到很好的控制,我用一个
Personally, because I want things to be able to be finely controlled, I use a
三扣鼠标.
three-button mouse.
用三键鼠标,一些事情你需要能够做到.
With a three-button mouse, some things you need to be able to do.
所以,如果你按鼠标中键,将鼠标左右移动,你可以
So if you press the middle mouse button and move your mouse left and right, you can
使用此工具绕您的天体运行。
use this to orbit around your object.
所以当你在3D软件中做任何事情时, 能够运行和确保
So as you do anything in a 3D software, the ability to orbit and make sure that
事情发生在你物体的前面,你的物体的后面,侧面
things are happening in the front of your object, the back of your object, the side
你的目标,你想要的方式,是关键。
of your object, the way you want it to be, is critical.
因此,鼠标中键旋转就是轨道.
So middle mouse button rotate is orbit.
如果你摇动鼠标中键, 我认为这应该是直观的,是
If you roll the middle mouse button, I think that should be intuitive to you, is
放大进退. 如果您在键盘上握有控制键, 或者命令于 a
zooming in and out. If you hold the control key on your keyboard, or command on a
Mac,然后按鼠标中键. 哦,对不起,不是命令,换班
Mac, and then press the middle mouse button. Oops, sorry, not command, shift.
变换按钮,然后鼠标中键,然后拖动它,你可以绕圈
The shift button, and then middle mouse button, and you drag it, you can pan around
你的工作空间。 好吧,所以如果你需要移动它的方式。
your working space. Okay, so if you need to move it that way.
所以再次,鼠标中键 本身,轨道。
So once again, middle mouse button by itself, orbit.
鼠标中间卷入和流出是缩放.
Middle mouse roll in and out is zoom.
然后转动和鼠标中键可以让你绕过屏幕。
And then shift and middle mouse button will allow you to pan around your screen.
如果你记不得了,这里有真的图标 你可以用
And if that's too much for you to remember, there are actual icons here you can use
做同样的事情。 所以,一个看起来像一个放大玻璃, 如果你离开
to do the same thing. So the one that looks like a magnifying glass, if you left
鼠标点击这个,然后拖上拖下,就可以放大.
mouse click on that, and then you drag it up and down, you can zoom.
手是锅。 所以,如果你离开鼠标点击, 你移动你的鼠标周围,
The hand is pan. So if you left mouse click on that and you move your mouse around,
你会跳下去的。 轨道需要使用这个,口香糖丸。
you'll pan. Orbit will require the use of this, the gumball.
如果你用鼠标左键点击口香糖灰色区域
So if you click in the gray area of the gumball with your left mouse button and
然后移动它周围,你可以旋转,抬头看,在你的物体上,因为那是
then move it around, you can rotate, look up, down on your object, because that's
跟轨道运行一样 摆 所以,现在关于口香糖球,你会
the same thing as orbiting. Okay. So now on the subject of the gumball, you'll
注意它以红、绿、蓝等多种友好颜色出现。
notice that it comes in multiple friendly colors like red, green, and blue.
那些东西和你们在Blender上看到的斧头相符
Those things correspond to the axes that you see here on Blender in
观景台 所以我们错过蓝色, 所以我可以继续去 覆盖和点击
the viewport. So we're missing blue, so I can go ahead and go to overlay and click
Z在这里显示蓝线。 好吧,我们走。
Z here to show the blue line as well. All right.
所以我希望你从现在开始做什么 或者想想 每当你在Blender工作的时候
So what I want you to do or think about from now on, whenever you work on Blender,
这是
is that
减Y,绿轴应该总是从左下角到
minus Y, the green axis should be always going from the lower left-hand corner to
右上角那个 这是Y轴。
the upper right-hand corner. That's the Y-axis.
X轴应该一直从左上角往下
The X-axis should always go from the upper left-hand corner down to the lower
右手边 然后是Z轴 从上到下 好吗
right-hand side, and then Z-axis, top to bottom, okay?
如果你用这种方式定位,那么你知道, 当我看着我的立方体在这里,这是
If you orient in this way, then you know that when I look at my cube here, this is
我对象的前脸 这是左边,当然是右边
the front face of my object. This is the left side, of course, the right side on
反面,背面,上,下。
the opposite side, the back, top, and bottom.
所以,每当你感到困惑 你所看到的,调整到这个
So whenever you get confused about what you're looking at, reorient to this
这个位置的定向是Y减,你知道你在看
orientation with minus Y in this location, and you know that you're looking at the
前脸你的东西,好吗? 我会告诉你为什么这很重要。
front face of your object, okay? And I'll tell you why that matters later.
所以,如果你想看看你物体的前脸, 你会点击负Y,
So if you want to look at the front face of your object, you'll click on minus Y,
它会撞到你物体的前面
and it will snap to the front of your object.
如果你想,或者, 如果你想看看你的物体的顶部,你可以
If you want, alternatively, if you want to look at the top of your object, you can
点击正Z, 它会向顶部跳动。
click on positive Z, and it will snap to the top.
现在很难理解 因为我们看着一个立方体和所有的脸
It's hard to understand right now because we're looking at a cube and all the faces
看上去是一样的,但只是一般的, 这就是你如何崩溃到不同的
look the same, but just generally, that's how you would snap to different
您对象的视图 。 好吧,我们走。
viewpoints of your object. All right.
我真的不想看到我的相机, 这是这个黑色三角形现在。
I really don't want to see my camera, which is this black triangle right now.
所以我可以到我的轮廓 点击相机旁边的眼球图标,
So I can go over to my outliner and click on the eyeball icon next to camera, and
这将会隐藏我的相机, 我将点击 做同样的事情
that's going to hide my camera, and I'm going to click to do the same thing to
轻 这样的话,那它就完全不参与我的模特工作了.
light. That way, then it's not involved in my modeling at all.
有问题吗? 导航技术好吗?
Any questions so far? Are we good with navigation?
你可以用拇指按键帮我
You can help me out by doing the thumbs up key,
或者给我一把拇指 让我知道 我说话的方式你可以
or just give me a thumbs up to let me know that I'm speaking in a way that you can
其实明白。 好吧,我们走。 有了这个,让我们开始玩这个立方体。
actually understand. All right. With that, let's start playing with this cube.
所以我们要从用户界面到操纵到查看模式
So we're going from user interface to manipulation to view mode,
对象模式, 用于当前立方体本身的工作 。
object mode, to now working on the cube itself.
所以要操纵任何对象,首先需要点击它来选择它.
So to manipulate any object, first you need to click on it to select it.
一旦选定了对象,你就会看到黄色的轮廓表明你
Once you've selected the object, you'll see a yellow outline indicating that you
已选择对象。 好吧,所以第一个键盘快捷键命令是
have selected the object. All right, so the first keyboard shortcut command is
按 G 键。
G.
G允许您移动对象.
G allows you to move the object.
现在,你问我 为什么它不是M移动? 为什么是G移动?
Now, you're asking me why is it not M for move? Why is it G for move?
因为M是Blender中别的东西使用的键盘快捷键,所以
It's because M is a keyboard shortcut used for something else in Blender, and so
他们用G来抓 所以,你抓住和移动物体。
they use G for grab. So you're grabbing and moving the object.
G就是这个意思,好吗? 所以,一旦你抓住它, 你可以移动它在哪里
That's what G stands for, okay? And so once you grab it, you can move it wherever
您想要在 3D 空间。
you want in 3D space.
如果你在命令的中间,你想取消它, 你击中逃跑
If you're in the middle of a command and you want to cancel it, you hit the escape
钥匙,它又回到你移动之前的位置。
key, and that brings it back to where it was before you moved it around.
如果你移动它,G,我离开鼠标点击 并把它留在一个
And if you move it, G, and I left mouse click and leave it at a
新的位置,你想回去,Z控制或Z指挥会带你回来
new position, and you want to go back, Control Z or Command Z will bring you back
将取消命令。 好吗? 这和很多其它软件一样
to, will undo the command. Okay? This is the same as many other software out there.
好吗? 现在,什么是很酷的, 和为什么我花了这么多时间
All right? Now, what's cool about it is, and the reason why I spent so much time on
X,Y,和Z 更早的时候,你可以限制立方体的运动或
X, Y, and Z earlier is you can constrain the motion of the cube or the
对象,在输入 G 键后添加一个轴修改符。
object by adding an axis modifier after you type the G key.
所以,如果我想在X轴上移动, 你会打G后面的X,现在
So if I want only to move in the X-axis, you would type G followed by X, and now
我只能用X轴移动 好吗? 逃而脱之.
I'm constrained to moving only on the X-axis. Okay? Escape to get out of that.
如果我想在Y轴上移动,它就是G和Y,然后我只移动在Y.
If I want to move on the Y-axis, it's G and Y, and then I move only in the Y.
如果我想只移动在Z轴, 它的G和Z, 然后上下移动
If I want to move only in the Z-axis, it's G and Z, and then moving up and down
仅此而已。 好吗? 因此,有这种限制是好的。
only. Okay? So it's good to have that constraint.
好吧,所以这是移动。 下一个转换命令是规模.
All right, so that's moving. The next transformation command is scale.
好吗? 让我们使立方体大小。
Okay? Let's make the cube bigger or smaller.
幸运的是,快捷键更容易记住。 这是S的尺度。
Luckily, the shortcut key is easier to remember. It's S for scale.
所以如果我打S,一行会... 我建议你使用
So if I type S, a line will-- Let me make a suggestion when you use the
缩放。 不要把你的光标直接放在物体上.
scale. Don't have your cursor directly on your object.
让它在你物体外一点
Have it be slightly outside your object.
按下S键,当你把鼠标拖离物体时,就会变大.
Hit the S key, and as you drag your mouse away from the object, it'll get bigger.
如果移动到物体的中心,就会变小. 好吗? 所以S键。
If you move it towards the center of the object, it'll get smaller. Okay? So S key.
则逃而脱之. 就像G一样,你可以添加轴修饰器
And Escape to get out of that. And just like G, you can add axis modifiers to
您的命令限制其规模。 所以我想让这个东西更高。
your command to constrain its scale. So I want to make this thing taller.
我会做S和Z,并把它限制在Z轴, 所以当我放大它,它只
I would do S and Z and constrain it to the Z-axis, so when I scale it, it only
缩放在一个方向上。 同样的,如果我想把它扩大,S和X,我可以做
scales in one direction. Similarly, if I want to make it wider, S and X, I can do
将其限制在X轴、S轴和Y轴上,使其从前到后更长或缩短
constrain it to the X-axis, S and Y to make it longer or shorter from front to
回来 摆
back. Okay.
最后但并非最不重要的是,转换键的第三个是旋转.
Last but not least, the third of the transformation keys is rotation.
快捷键R. 好吗? 和其他一样,如果你用
Shortcut key R. Okay? And similar to the other ones, if you modify that with
例如,当修改为 Z 轴时,它会随轴旋转
a axis, like for instance, when modified to the Z-axis, it will rotate with the
蓝线作为它的旋转中心.
blue line as its center of rotation.
同样,R,
Similarly, R,
X将使用红线作为其旋转中心,以及
X will use the red line as its center of rotation, and
R,Y将使用绿线作为旋转中心.
R, Y will use the green line as the center of rotation.
如果不使用任何修改键,则旋转轴
If you do not use any of the modifier keys and you do rotation, the axis
它会用来旋转 将是你的脸和
that it will use for the rotation will be the imaginary axis between your face and
屏幕。 所以,如果我现在做R 旋转它, 它使用这个想象的线
the screen. So if I do R right now and rotate it, it uses this imaginary line
介于面部和屏幕之间,作为旋转的中心。
between face and screen as the center of rotation.
摆 目前情况如何?
Okay. Good so far?
不错 好吧,我们走。 谢谢你,蒂娜,你的拇指。
Good. All right. Thank you, Tina, for the thumbs up.
让我觉得我知道自己在做什么
Makes me feel infinitely better that I know what I'm doing.
好吧,所以在这之后, 让我们去操纵 这个立方体的细微方面。
All right, so after this, let's go on and manipulate the fine aspects of this cube.
这是一个非常无聊的立方体 现在。 让我们做一些有趣的事情。
It's a really boring cube right now. Let's do something fun.
我提到,我们目前处于物体模式。
I mentioned that we are currently in object mode.
为了得到微观调整,我们需要进入编辑模式.
In order to get to micro adjustments, we need to go into edit mode.
在对象切换之间、对象模式和编辑模式之间的快捷键
The shortcut key to get between object to toggle, between object mode and edit mode
是键盘上的 Tab 键。 所以,如果你打塔布, 你会看到顶端左
is the Tab key on your keyboard. So if you hit Tab, you'll see that the top left
窗口从这里更改
window here changes from
对象编辑,您注意到您的立方体现在具有额外的特性。
object to edit, and you notice that your cube has extra features now.
它有这些小点, 好吧,在角落,例如。
It has these little dots, okay, on the corners, for instance.
因此,如果我选择外 取消任何选择, 我选择这个特别
And so if I select outside to deselect anything, and I select this particular
转角,然后现在我可以 应用任何我的转换键,对不对?
corner, and then now I can apply any of my transformation keys, right?
如果我打G的移动或抓, 现在我可以移动那个角落,我可以开始
If I hit G for move or grab, now I can just move that corner, and I can start
到处玩它的形状。 摆
playing around with its shape. Okay.
我可以走这个拐角,我可以像以前一样把它限制在轴上。
I can take this corner, and I can constrain it to axis just like before.
例如,G和Z,我可以移动这个角落, 我可以拿这个,
For instance, G and then Z, I can move this corner up, and I can take this one and
我可以说G和X,我可以把它移动到X方向。
can say G and X, I can move it in the X direction.
现在我有一个比立方体更有趣的东西。
And now I have a much more interesting object than a cube.
类似地,你可以缩放事物。 哦,我忘了提了,有三个选择
Similarly, you can scale things. Oh, I forgot to mention, there are three selection
在编辑模式中可以使用的模式。
modes that are possible in edit mode.
目前,我们处于顶点选择模式,这意味着你可以选择其中之一。
Currently, we're in the vertex select mode, which means you can select one of the
在角落的点。 这里的中间,首先,顶点选择模式,
dots at the corner. The middle one here, first of all, the vertex select mode, the
快捷键是键盘上的第一。
shortcut key for that is the number one on your keyboard.
第二个选择模式是边缘选择模式,这在键盘上是两个.
The second selection mode is edge select mode, and that's two on your keyboard.
如果你处于边缘选择模式,而不是选择角,你会选择
If you're in edge select mode, instead of selecting corners, you'll be selecting
定义您所在的许多边缘之一
one of the many edges that defines your
对象。 就像以前一样 你可以使用任何转换命令 移动
object. And just like before, you can use any of the transformation commands, move,
缩放,在选择时旋转。 所以我要去G,我可以移动它。
scale, rotate on your selection. So I'm going to G and I can move it.
我可以缩放它。 我可以旋转它,选中的
I can S to scale it. I can R to rotate it, the selected
边缘。 摆 现在,就像我说的,我有一个更有趣的东西。
edge. Okay. And now, like I said, I have a much more interesting object now.
最后但并非最不重要的是,如果你在键盘上放三个,你就可以选择面部
Last but not least, if you put three on your keyboard, you get to the face select
模式,然后选择对象的面部。
mode, and you'll select one of the faces of the object that you have.
再说一次 你可以操纵它 所以,G,我可以移动它在这里,
And again, you can manipulate it. So G, I can move it out here,
R来旋转,随便你
R to rotate it, whatever you want to do.
好吗?
Okay?
到目前为止,这样好吗? 所以编辑模式,微调整,所有转换
So far, so good? So edit mode, micro adjustments, all of the transformation
您早先使用的指令, 包括轴限制, 将在
commands that you used earlier, including the axis constraints, will work on the
对象。 我要还给你
object. I'm going to return it to
此处的立方体形式通过撤消
the cube form here by doing undo
许多,很多次。 还有一件事,你注意到我做了26次
many, many times. And one thing, you notice that I've done 26 undos to get
我的操控器回到立方体。
my manipulations back to the cube.
当你进入Blender时 我要做的第一件事就是增加人数
The first thing I would do whenever you get into Blender is to increase the number
你有能力使用的东西
of undos that you're capable of using.
所以,你这样做 通过去编辑,首选,
So you do that by going to Edit, Preferences,
系统 这里的记忆极限,有
System. And here under Memory Limits, there's
a 分类称为 Undo 步骤。 默认是16步或32步之类的.
a category called Undo Steps. The default is something like 16 steps or 32 steps.
我做了150 因为我总是犯错误 我想能够
I made mine 150 because I make mistakes all the time, and I want to be able to
重做,撤销,撤销,撤销, 得到一个点,我很高兴。
redo, undo, undo, undo, and get to a point where I'm happy with.
这是一种方式 排序,
That's one way to sort of,
来控制历史,修改对象的历史。
to control the history, the modification history to your object.
另一个非常有用的方法,我还没有这样做, 为了拯救我的物体或
Another very useful way, and I haven't done this yet, to save my object or
我的文件,你不应该惊讶, 这是控制+S或命令+S,
my file, you shouldn't be surprised, it's Control + S or Command + S, and this
保存它, 你可以保存它 无论你想在哪里。
saves it, and you can save it wherever you want.
今以教名存此经.
I'm going to save it here under the name Tutorial.
摆 像这样 救赎.
Okay. Like that. Save.
现在我要对这里的物体 进行一系列的操纵
And now I'm going to make a bunch of manipulations to my object here.
其实,你知道吗? 没关系
Well, actually, you know what? No, it's okay.
然后,我不知道,移动这个像这样, 拿着这张脸,
And then, I don't know, move this like this, take this face,
旋转一下,走这边
rotate it, take this corner
向上移动 好吧,这就是我的新对象。
and move it up. Okay, so that's my new object.
现在,我不百分之百确定我喜欢这个物体, 也许我想回到立方体。
Now, I'm not 100% sure I like this object, and maybe I want to go back to the cube.
因此,一个保存不同版本同一文件的方法是在File下,
So one way to save different versions of the same file is under File,
这里有"保存","保存","保存副本",最后一张在这里,"保存递增".
there's Save, Save As, Save Copy, and the last one here, Save Incremental.
所以如果我选择增量保存,我告诉你,我的文件名称是现在
So if I choose Save Incremental, I told you that my file name is currently
教书,但如果我节省增量, 我的档案现在的名字是教书
Tutorial, but if I do save incremental, my name of my file is now Tutorial
1. 现在我有两个形状相同的文件。
1. So now I have two files that have the same shape.
我有教书和教书一。 如果因为什么原因我不喜欢我拥有的东西
I have Tutorial and Tutorial 1. And if for whatever reason I don't like what I've
刚刚完成的,我可以返回 回到文件,打开最近,教学,
just done here, I can revert back by going to File, Open Recent, Tutorial,
我可以回到我的立方体形状。 好吗?
and I can go back to my cube shape. Okay?
所以如果你做了一个非常复杂的模型, 而且你不是1000 %确定
So if you're doing an incredibly complex model, and you're not 1,000% sure that
你接下来要做的是 毁掉你创造的所有优秀作品
what you do next is going to destroy all of the wonderful work you've created so
远处,您可以节省增量来保存不同的
far, you can do save incremental to save different
在你的文件中的里程碑点, 所以你不会弄乱 一些精彩的工作,
milestone points within your file so you don't mess up some wonderful work that
你以前做过,你还得回去
you've done before, and you have a point to return to.
你听到了吗? 可以吗? 拇指起来,蒂娜? 好吧,我们走。 真不错
Did you catch that? Is that okay? Thumbs up, Tina? All right. Wonderful.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
好吧,所以,一个新的命令给你 现在,我们正在编辑模式。
All right, so, a new command for you now that we're in edit mode.
我提到你可以拿这些顶点来操纵它。
I mentioned that you can take these vertices and manipulate it.
如果你想玩更多的顶点呢? 让我们改变这个东西的形状。
What if you want more vertices to play with? Let's change the shape of this thing.
我要从这个可爱的立方体里快速做个香水瓶,好吗?
I'm going to quickly make a perfume bottle out of this lovely cube, okay?
所以,我要做的是 我要打A为所有人,
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to hit A for all,
我要把它放大到Y方向 把它压碎
and I'm going to scale it in the Y direction to squash it.
然后我要做一个香奈儿瓶子 比如说,对不对?
Then I'm going to make a Chanel bottle, for instance, right?
因此,在Y方向的尺度。 我要把它挤进一点点 给它
So scale in the Y direction. I'm going to squeeze it in a little bit to give it
其实,我不知道香奈儿瓶子是什么样子
more of a-- Actually, I don't know what a Chanel bottle looks like.
这将会是我的版本 香奈尔瓶。
This is going to be my version of a Chanel bottle.
但是,好吧,所以我们需要某种
But, all right, so we're going to need some kind of
脖子给我的瓶子 然后
neck for my bottle and then
我瓶子的顶盖 因此,我并没有增加一堆几何, 我只是去
a top cap for my bottle. So instead of adding a bunch of geometry, I'm just going
用我现有的几何学来操纵它
to take my existing geometry and manipulate it.
将三击进入面部选择模式,我将选择顶部表面.
Hitting three to go into face select mode, I'm going to select the top surface.
我用我的命令来做一个陷害,
I use the I command to do an inset,
好吧,创建一个新的子面。
okay, to create a new kind of sub-face.
我将放大这个小面 通过缩放在X使其更加平坦
I'm going to scale this sub-face to make it more square by scaling it in the X
要让它更加平坦
direction to make it more square.
好吗? 我要敲E键 以放大形状。
All right? I'm going to hit the E key to extrude the shape up.
好吧,所以这是我的脖子 我的香水瓶。 现在我要做这个盖子。
Okay, so that's my neck of my perfume bottle. Now I'm going to make the cap.
所以,我可以做的是 我将再次挤压它。
So what I can do is I'm going to extrude it one more time.
但首先我想大一点, 所以我要做E,然后S。
But first I want to go bigger, so I'm going to do E and followed by S.
因此,挤压和规模 同时做相反的 内置和去
So extrude and scale at the same time to do the opposite of inset and go on the
外面像这样。 摆 然后从这架平板飞机上,我要上去,
outside like this. Okay. And then from this flat plane, I'm going to go up,
E要上去了,这是我的香水瓶帽子
E to go up, this is going to be my perfume bottle hat.
更有意思的是,我要把顶部放大一点
And to make it more interesting, I'm going to scale the top a little bit to give it
略显形体.
a little bit of shape.
然后再次挤压它,再次缩放,
And then extrude it again, scale it again,
并再次挤压它。 好吧,这就是我可爱的香水瓶
and extrude it one more time. All right, so this is my lovely perfume bottle made
刚刚被挤出 和一点点的缩放。 摆
out of just inset extrusion and a little bit of scaling. Okay.
我要击打Tab,回到物体模式 击打G,Z,把这个移到上面
I'm going to hit Tab to go back into object mode and hit G, Z to move this up above
工作飞机。
the work plane.
好吧,现在我们要去
All right, now we're going to
给它一些材料。 有了这个物体,我要去红色
give it some materials. With this object selected, I'm going to go to the red
在此属性窗口上的 checker ball,单击 New 创建新材料。
checker ball on the properties window here, click New to create a new material.
故香水瓶底应净玻璃.
So the bottom of the perfume bottle should be clear glass.
所以,我要做的是, 首先,我叫这个事情清楚
So what I'm going to do is, first I'm going to call this thing clear
杯子。 。 。 。 实际上,我要把它弄成蓝色,以便有一点颜色。
glass. Actually, I'm going to make it blue so that there's a little bit of color.
蓝玻璃.
Blue glass.
目前,这里的表面类型叫做Princed BSDF.
And currently, the surface type here is called Principled BSDF.
我不想那样 我想这样
I don't want that. I want it to be
杯子。 。 。 。 所以我要点击这个原则BSDF, 而不是选择格拉斯BSDF。
glass. So I'm going to click this Principled BSDF, and instead choose Glass BSDF.
我将点击"彩色"并修改为略为蓝色.
I'm going to click on Color and change it to be slightly blue.
如果你想看看是什么样子, 你可以去预览,你可以看到
And if you want to see what that looks like, you can go to Preview and you can see
这就是它的样子。 我要拿粗糙的值来做
this is what it would look like. I'm going to take the roughness value and make it
至零,使它变得非常,非常闪亮和清晰。
to zero so that it becomes very, very shiny and clear.
现在,如果我去伦德预览, 这里的第三个视图模式, 你可以看到我的
And now if I go to Render Preview, the third view mode here, you can see that my
对象,
object,
还没有通过 因为我没有进入完全渲染模式
it's not see-through yet because I'm not in full render mode.
如果我去完全渲染模式,
If I go to full render mode,
好吧,我打开灯。
okay, and I turn on my light.
我的灯呢? 在这里。 控制G,X,我们移到这里
Where's my light? Over here. Control G, X. Let's move it here.
需要让我的光变强一点,我想。 为什么它不出现?
Need to make my light a little bit stronger, I guess. Why is it not showing up?
瓳
Huh.
好吧 我不喜欢这个光
All right, I don't like this light.
我要通过点击键盘上的删除键来删除这个光线.
I'm going to delete this light by hitting the delete key on my keyboard.
我准备去A班 所以换A
I'm going to Shift A to add. So Shift A.
在对象模式建模窗口中,Shift A允许您添加任何东西.
When you're in the object mode modeling window, Shift A allows you to add anything.
它允许您添加一个新的几何. 它允许你添加一个新的光。
It allows you to add a new geometry. It allows you to add a new light.
所以这里我要增加一个区域光线。 我喜欢区灯
So here I'm going to add an area light. I like area lights.
G,Z来移动区域光线,S来放大它,所以它有点大.
G, Z to move the area light up, S to scale it so it's a little bit bigger.
然后我会去 -
Then I'm going to go to--
当我选择灯光,属性菜单 改变一点点,我有在
When I select the light, the properties menu changes a little bit and I have at the
绿色的灯泡图标,现在光的力量就是
very bottom a light bulb icon in green, and right now the power of that light is
10,我会做1000, 看看我是否得到更多的光在我的物体。
10. I'm going to make that 1,000 and see if I get more light on my object.
为什么不告诉我清楚? 也许我需要再加一点
Why is it not showing me clear? Maybe I need to add one more thing.
我要在这个场景的底部增加一架飞机. 飞机
I'm going to add a plane at the bottom of this scene. Mesh, plane.
放大一点
Scale it up
所以它有东西看。
so that it has something to look at.
我要点击红色检查板图标 让飞机颜色变黑
I'm going to click on the red checkerboard icon and make the plane black color
或者灰色这样... 单单
or gray so that-- Oh, wait a minute.
我不太清楚为什么我不... 嗯,不,这是透明的。
I'm not quite sure why I'm not-- Well, no, it is transparent.
你可以看到黄线正在穿过这里的后面。
You can kind of see that the yellow line is crossing through the back of this.
我觉得我必须把它弄明白
I think I have to render this in order to get it to be clear.
总之,你必须接受我的话 这瓶酒现在有杯子
Anyway, you'll have to take my word for it that currently this bottle has a glass
特性。 现在,你对我说:"我不想让这东西的顶部是玻璃.
feature. Now you're saying to me, "I don't want the top of this thing to be glass.
我希望它是,说, 黑色塑料或类似的东西。
I want it to be, say, black plastic or something like that.
我怎样才能把物资分配本地化呢?" 您输入了编辑模式。
How can I localize material assignment?" You do that by entering into edit mode.
所以 Tab 可以进入编辑模式. 我要打到三个人 做面部选择,我
So Tab to get into edit mode. I'm going to hit three to do face select, and I'm
首先,我需要增加一个新的材料。
going to select the-- First of all, I need to add a new material.
所以,我要去这里,点击的加, 确保你是在红色
So I'm going to go over here, click on the plus, make sure you're in the red
复选板图标。 点击加号以添加第二个材料 。
checkerboard icon. Click plus to add a second material.
点击 New, 让我们把顶部的亮度做成红色 。 我不知道.
Click New, and let's make the top bright red. I don't know.
我知道Coco Chanel会用这么恐怖的颜色对我大喊大叫 但是
I know Coco Chanel would be screaming at me for using such horrific colors, but
我要说红塑料
I'll say red plastic
作为名字。 你可以玩的粗糙 让它少或更闪亮,上
as the name. And you can play with the roughness to make it less or more shiny, up
给你的。 我要通过减少粗糙度来使它变得非常闪亮.
to you. I'm going to make it very shiny by reducing the roughness.
现在,为了把这个应用到上面, 我要点击的脸
And now, to apply that to the top part here, I'm going to click on the face that
我想这么做 I want. 如果按住转向键,可以继续选择其他面孔.
I want. If you hold down the shift key, you can continue to select other faces.
好吧,我要去旋转这个周围, 确保我得到的一切旋转周围。
Okay, I'm going to rotate this around, make sure I get everything rotated around.
好吧,这就是我想要的红色塑料部分。
All right, so this is the part I want to be red plastic.
确保你选择红色塑料, 和下面有一个叫"指定"的按钮。
Make sure you select red plastic, and underneath there's a button called Assign.
当我点击 Assign 时, 这个对象的顶部将会是不同的
When I click Assign, the top of this object is now going to be a different
物质。 这就是你如何完成本地化的物质任务。 好吗?
material. So that's how you do localized material assignment. Okay?
好吧,所以现在你有一个不这么漂亮的物体, 想看看它是什么样子
All right, so now you have a not so beautiful object, and want to see what it looks
就像你做它,好吗? 这里我们回到属性菜单,
like if you render it, okay? Here's where we go back to the properties menu, the
非常顶级的图标,第二到顶级的图标,它看起来像DSLR的背面.
very top icon, the second to top icon, which looks like the back of the DSLR.
好吧,现在我们是在EV模式。 也许这就是为什么,你叫它什么?
Okay, right now we are in EV mode. That's probably why the, what do you call it?
透明度表现得不太好。
The transparency is not showing up very well.
顺便说一句,EV是电影"流"中用来 做它的全部
By the way, EV was what was used in the movie Flow to do the entirety of its
动画渲染. 我有一个相当好的计算机 与图形卡,所以我
animation rendering. I have a reasonably good computer with a graphics card, so I'm
将去使用循环,这是一个更先进,更现实的渲染
going to go and use Cycles, which is a more advanced, more realistic rendering
模式。 事实上,我会确保我的GPU 参与渲染
mode. And in fact, I'm going to make sure that my GPU is involved in the rendering
进程。 我会给你做个样本
process. And I'm going to just do a sample render here for you.
所以,最多样本,我只是要 减少为32 现在使这个去
So max samples, I'm just going to reduce this to 32 for now to make this go a
有点快。 为了展现出这个形象
little bit faster. And to render out this image,
您需要设置相机来查看这个图像 。
you need to set the camera to look at this image.
这会很快的,我很抱歉。
This is going to go fast, my apologies.
所以,视图,
So View,
对齐视图,将活动相机对齐到视图,像这样.
Align View, Align Active Camera to View, like so.
然后,我需要敲N键 弹出这边,去Video,
And then I need to hit the N key to pop out the side here, go to View,
并点击锁定到3D光标和相机查看。
and hit Lock to 3D Cursor and Camera to View.
然后,我可以放大 进出 使我的物体 在我的视野端口,当我
And then I can zoom in and out to position my object nicely into my view port as I
想要这个 好吧,我们就这样算了 N 键以隐藏侧面板 。
want it. Okay, we'll leave it like that. N key to hide the side panel.
然后你去伦德,伦德图像,
And then you go to Render, Render Image,
它会揭示你的形象。
and it will render out your image.
好吧,现在你可以看到,它是玻璃和塑料, 好吧,因为我们试图制造
Okay, and you can see now that it's glass and plastic, okay, as we tried to make
这个 当然,你可以花更多的时间 照明和物质调整
it. Of course, you could spend a lot more time on lighting and material adjustments
让这更美丽 但这是开始
to get this to be more beautiful, but this is the beginning of it.
一旦你有你喜欢的渲染, 如果你想真正下载它
Once you have a rendering that you like, if you want to actually download it for
在文档中使用什么的,你可以去图像,保存,然后
use in your documentation or whatever, you can go to Image, Save, and then
显然,选择一个地方。 我会把它保存到下载,我会把它叫做
obviously choose a place. I'm going to save it into downloads, and I'll call it
教程渲染。
tutorial render.
好吧,所以现在如果我去 我的视窗探索器,
Okay, so now if I go to my Windows Explorer,
去下载,我这里有一个文件,叫做教程,我可以... 是你吗?
go to Downloads, I have a file here called tutorial render that I can-- Are you
看着它? 我希望你能看见 你看到我的Windows探索器了吗? 是的,你是这样。
looking at it? I'm hoping you see it. You seeing my Windows Explorer? Yes, you are.
好吧,所以我双击 教学图像。
Okay, so I double-click on tutorial image.
你会明白的
You'll see that
我有一个我展示出来的形象。
I have this image that I rendered out.
好吧,所以这是一个荒谬的快速巡演 通过基本
All right, so that was a ridiculously fast tour through the fundamentals of
布莱德
Blender.
你们中有多少人在惊慌失措 对你决定加入本届会议感到后悔
How many of you are panicking that you regret your decision to join this session
今天吗?
today?
好吧,到目前为止好吗?
All right, so far so good?
摆
Okay.
好,我要把可爱的飞机和香水藏起来
All right, I'm going to hide my lovely plane and perfume
瓶子,我要去 模拟别的东西。
bottle, and I'm going to model up something else.
我要模拟一个非常简单的卡通人物 给你看一些其他的
I'm going to model up a very simple cartoon character and to show you some other
如果您想要模拟, 您需要的技术
techniques that you will need if you want to model up
衣服还是什么的 摆 本周的关键内容之一是网格
clothing or whatever. Okay. One of the key aspects of this week is mesh
Blender是一个网络操作软件。
manipulation, and Blender is a mesh manipulation software.
让我举个例子。 我们曾经的飞机 是背景或
So let me give you an example. The plane that we used to be the background or the
我们现场的地板
floor of our scene
刚刚
is just
如所示。 这只是一个公寓
as it is indicated. It's just a flat
平面图。 如果我打中的话
square plane. If I hit
要进入编辑模式,我看到它有四个角。
Tab to go into edit mode, I see that it has four corners.
这是零分层的网状网状网,好吗?
So this is a mesh with zero subdivisions, okay?
现在我要用鼠标点击和撞击 把它变成真正的网状
Now I'm going to turn it into a real mesh by right mouse clicking and hitting
潜化. 所以现在,而不是作为一个
Subdivide. So now instead of being one
里面有一个形状的飞机 有四架飞机
plane with one shape inside, it's got four planes.
我将再次这样做,再细分一次,再细分一次,再细分一次.
I'm going to do that again, subdivide one more time, one more time, one more time.
这是网状的 它是一个表面,上面有许多控制点。
So this is a mesh. It is a surface with lots of control points on top of it.
所以,如果我回去,打一个进入顶点模式, 这个表面现在有很多很多
So if I go back, hit one to go into vertex mode, this surface now has lots and lots
我可以操纵的要点 所以,想象这是手帕 我想
of points that I can manipulate. So imagine this is a handkerchief and I want to
让它看起来很流畅 之类的东西。
make it look all flowy and stuff like that.
我可以进去 选择其中的几个点, 转动键和选择几个
I can go in here and select a couple of these points, shift key and select a few of
这些顶点,并做GZ移动它上去。 好吗?
these vertices and do GZ to move it up. Okay?
但这并不令人满意,因为只有这些点正在上升。
But that's not very satisfying because only those points are moving up.
所以,你可以做的是有一个按钮 在这里的顶部, 这是一个圆形的,
So what you can do is there's a button up in the top here, which is a circle shape,
或快捷键 O,将允许您进行名为比例编辑的工作。
or the shortcut key O, will allow you to do something called proportional editing.
比例编辑不仅允许您操纵
Proportional editing will allow you to not only manipulate the
你刚刚选择的顶点, 但它周围的邻居也一样
vertices that you just selected, but its surrounding neighbors as well to the
程度你控制。 好吗? 所以,现在如果我做GZ, 你会看到有一个灰色
degree that you control. Okay? So now if I do GZ, you'll see that there's a gray
转圈,如果我滚开我的鼠标按钮, 它会越来越小。
circle there that if I roll my mouse button, it gets bigger and smaller.
这个灰色的圆圈是影响范围.
This gray circle is the area of influence.
所以之前的动作... 所以我要关机了
So the move before-- So I'm going to turn off
比例编辑. 再说一次,如果我用GZ来把这些点向上移动,它只会
proportional editing. And once again, if I do GZ to move these dots upward, it only
把那些点拉起来 周围的每一个点 都没有受到影响
pulls up those dots, and every other dot around it doesn't get affected at all.
然而,如果我打开比例编辑与O 或者点击这个按钮在这里,
However, if I turn on proportional editing with O or click this button up here and
做GZ,视我的势力范围大小, 它会提出它的
do GZ, depending on the size of my area of influence, it will bring up its
邻居也一样。
neighbors as well.
好吗? 所以,如果我把圆圈变小,影响就会变小。
Okay? So if I make the circle smaller, the influence is smaller.
如果我把圆圈变大, 它影响更多的表面,
If I make the circle bigger, it influences more of the surface, the
我在玩游戏
mesh that I'm playing with.
酷,对不对? 我想这对你们来说应该是一个精彩的时刻。
Cool, right? I think that this should be a wow moment for some of you.
好吧,所以一个顶点。 现在我要再操控一次这个GZ
Okay, so one vertex. Now I'm going to try to manipulate this GZ one more time and
缩小影响范围,并拖动它。
reduce the area of influence and drag this up.
你可以动态地做。 当你拉起来,你可以改变什么
And you can do it dynamically. As you pull it up, you can change what gets
被操纵。
manipulated.
这么酷。 所以比例编辑,快捷键 O. 好吗?
So very cool. So proportional editing, shortcut key O. Okay?
网格模特 好了,现在让我们去 - 我要返回控制+Z返回
Mesh modeling. Okay, so now let's go-- I'm going to return to Control + Z to return
所有这些事情都恢复正常了
all of these things back to normal.
返回标签
Tab to go back into
对象模式。 我要把我的飞机藏起来,现在我们要模拟。
object mode. I'm going to hide my plane, and now we're going to model up.
你们中有多少人知道我们的游戏?
How many of you know the game Among Us?
你知道我们之间的游戏吗? 你们谁带孩子都笑 因为你
Do you know this game Among Us? Any of you with children are smiling because you
非常清楚我在说什么。
know very well what I'm talking about.
好吧,你知道我要为你们这些显然不是
Okay, you know what I'm going to bring up for the rest of you who are obviously not
非常酷,我需要教你们我们之间是什么。 让我告诉你。
very cool, I need to teach you what Among Us is. Let me show you.
它是一个豆状的人物 它看起来像这样。 好吗?
It is a bean-shaped character that looks something like this. Okay?
我用这个教孩子们 如何在Blender上做3D模特
I use this to teach my kids how to do 3D modeling on Blender.
所以我们现在要演一个《我们中的人物》。
So we're going to do an Among Us character right now.
好吧,我们走。 因此,令人惊讶的是,我要去 Shift + A,加一个立方体。 你会说:"什么?
All right. So surprisingly, I'm going to Shift + A, add a cube. You're like, "What?
It豆形. 为什么你要用立方体开始呢?" 我为什么
It's a bean shape. Why the heck are you starting off with a cube?" The reason I
从立方体开始是因为...
start off with a cube is because the few--
想在Blender上做模特 就像你在雕塑一样
Think of modeling on Blender like you're sculpting.
你要从块材料开始, 你将创建一个
You're going to start off with a block of material, and you're going to create a
先是粗糙的形状 然后慢慢地细化成它的光滑
rough shape of it first and then slowly refine it into its smooth,
你最终会想做的事
curvaceous face that you'll end up wanting to do.
所以,如果你看 人们雕塑的照片, 开始的形状,
So if you look at pictures of people sculpting sculptures, the beginning shape of
是非常,非常粗糙。 我们之所以想这样做,是因为
it is very, very rough. And the reason we want to do that is the fewer number of
Blender模式中存在的面孔,需求越少
faces that are present in a Blender modeling situation, the less demand
它会在你的电脑上。 如果你马上把一千个小区放进去
it will be on your computer. If you immediately put 1,000 subdivisions onto this
立方体,然后你试图移动 它会让你的计算机非常,
cube and then you try to move it around, it's going to make your computer very,
慢慢地,它会发热而发热。
very slow, and it's going to heat up and get hot.
所以我们要用最少的形状来创造它。
So we're going to create this by using the least amount of shapes that we can.
然而,我要在这里使用一个修饰符.
However, I'm going to use a modifier here.
因为它是豆形,我要去 添加修饰剂,生成子
Because it's a bean shape, I'm going to go add modifier, generate subdivision
把它变成一个一般像豆子的东西 好吗?
surface to turn it into something that generally looks like a bean. Okay?
这将成为我的起点。
And this is going to be my starting point.
我要把一级改为二级 给它一个
I'm going to change the level viewport from level one to level two to give it a
稍微多一点的分支, 但不会太多。
little bit more subdivisions, but not too many.
然后我要应用这个修饰符。 我很高兴。
And then I'm going to apply this modifier. I'm happy.
我希望它是圆的,所以不要让它 无损和预览,我可以
I want it to be round, so instead of leaving it non-destructive and preview, I can
点击此向下箭头, 点击应用 。
click on this down arrow, click Apply.
让我告诉你,当你不应用它会发生什么。
Let me show you what happens when you don't apply it.
因此,从对象模式,如果我点击Tab 进入编辑模式,它仍然认为
So from object mode, if I hit Tab to go into edit mode, it still thinks of this
对象为立方体。 对吧? 我们可以用这种方式来操纵它。
object as a cube. Right? And we can actually manipulate it in this way.
举例来说,如果我把它放大到Z方向, 我可以把这个伸展到更多
For instance, if I scale it in the Z direction, I can stretch this out to be more
譬如在保持立方体的同时,
like the Among Us character while maintaining a cube.
而且它仍然是,因为它认为它是一个立方体,对计算机的要求较低.
And it's still, because it thinks it's a cube, it's less demanding on the computer.
对吧? "我们中"这个角色比较平坦,所以我要在Y里放大
Right? The Among Us character is more flat, so I'm going to scale it in the Y
方向,S -Y来放大, 平整它一点点像这样。
direction, S-Y to scale it, to flatten it a little bit like this.
好吗? 而G -Z移动它上 工作飞机上 因为他的腿,
Okay? And G-Z to move it up above the work plane because he's going to have legs,
和要返回的对象模式。 好吧,这就是我的开始
and object mode to go back. All right, so that's the beginning of my Among Us
字符键。 但从这一点,我想 能够进入所有这些小
character. But from this point, I want to be able to access all of these little
内部分区
subdivisions within
我刚刚做的几何 所以我必须应用这个修饰符。
the geometry I just made. So I'm going to have to apply this modifier.
所以,去与下箭,打应用, 现在当我打塔布,我回去。
So go with the down arrow, hit Apply, and now when I hit Tab, I go back in.
其下各分所烧入. 好吗?
It's got all of the subdivisions baked into it. Okay?
所以,如你所见,我想,让我看看。 如果我再回我身边一次
So as you saw, I think, let me see. If I go back to Among Us one more time.
这个角色非常,非常简单. 其特征仅有少数.
This character is very, very simple. It's got only a few features.
其面有 face,背有 backpack,两条腿.
It's got a face, it's got a backpack, and it's got two legs.
所以这就是我们要做的模型。
So that's what we're going to do to model.
并且因为它的对称性, 我不想要模型 两条手臂,两条腿,和
And because it's symmetrical, I don't want to have to model two arms, two legs, and
诸如此类. 我能做的是模拟这个物体的一半。
so on and so forth. What I can do is to model only half of this object.
我在这里
So here I am in
以负 Y 编辑模式。 好,我想确定负 Y 正在面对这个模式
edit mode with minus Y. Okay, I want to make sure minus Y is facing in this
方向,我知道这里,减去Y。 所以这是我的人的正面。
direction, and I know here, minus Y. So this is the front of my guy.
这里有一个按钮,这是两个方块相互重叠.
There's a button here, which is two squares overlapping one another.
这是X光模式。 所以,如果我点击这个, 我可以看到我的物体上的点, 两个在
This is X-ray mode. So if I click on that, I can see the dots on my object, both in
前面和后面 我会告诉你为什么这很重要
the front and the back, and I'll show you why this is important.
如果我没有打开X射线模式... ...我直接从...
If I don't have X-ray mode turned on and I look at this object directly from the
前面我用鼠标左键拖动来进行这样的选择,
front and I do a selection like this with a left mouse click drag,
它会选择它能看见的所有顶点 但后面的所有顶点
it selects all of the vertices that it can see, but all the vertices in the back
未选择无法看到。 好吗? 我不想那样
that it cannot see is not selected. Okay? I don't want that.
现在,我想能够同时选择前后, 所以我打开
Right now, I want to be able to select front and back simultaneously, so I turn on
X射线模式,所以我可以看到前后两面.
X-ray mode, so I can see both front and back.
当我选择一半的物体时 它从前面选择一切
And now when I do selection of half of the object, it selects everything from front
到后面来。 这是一个非常有用的工具,好吗?
to back. It's a very useful tool, okay?
我要删除一半这些东西 通过点击X删除和选择
I'm going to delete half all of these things by hitting X for delete and choosing
要删除面孔, 而我留下半个豆。 好吗?
to delete faces, and I'm left with a half of a bean. Okay?
现在我要用另一种修饰剂
And now I'm going to use another modifier.
我将选择A来选择所有, 去添加修改器,生成镜像,
I'm going to select A to select all, go to add modifier, generate mirror, and
这会为我创造另一半。
it's going to create the other half for me.
并确保当您使用镜像修饰器时,您也选择剪辑。
And make sure that when you use the mirror modifier, that you also select clipping.
好吗? 这很重要。 很多人会忘记做这个,它创造了一个
Okay? This is very important. A lot of you will forget to do this, and it creates a
乱七八糟的 在使用镜像修饰器时, 请选择剪辑 。
mess. Make sure you select clipping when you use the mirror modifier.
好吧,那我为什么要这么做? 因为现在我改变这一面
Okay, so why am I doing this? Is because now when I make changes on this side, it
自动反射到另一边 这让我省了很多时间。
automatically gets reflected on the other side as well. It saves me a lot of time.
好极了,不错
Okay, wonderful.
让我们创造一张脸。 我该怎么做?
Let's create a face. So how do I do that?
击三下... 首先,我要关机
Hit three to-- First of all, I'm going to turn off
X射线模式只是为了不意外地在物体的后面选择一些东西.
X-ray mode just so I don't accidentally select something in the back of the object.
按三键进行面部选择 。 我会
Hit three to do face select. I'm going to
单击并选择这四个面孔。
click and select these four faces.
我可以做到这一点,通过握住 转动键,只是做到这一点。
I can do that by holding down the shift key and just doing this.
或者更快的方法就是让鼠标点击并拖动并交叉
Or a faster way to do it is to left mouse click and drag and kind of intersect
这四件事是可取的。 这是你的脸,好吗?
those four desirable things. And this is going to be your face, okay?
有了这四张面孔,你就会在键盘上打E
With these four faces selected, you're going to hit E on your keyboard for extrude,
你会给脸打一拳
and you're going to punch it out a little bit for the face.
将如是观. 现在我要回到物体的后面
It's going to look like that. Now I'm going to go back to the back of the object,
我要做一个背包。 好吗?
and I'm going to do a backpack. Okay?
所以再次选择我想要的
So once again, selecting the ones I want,
我觉得 是啊,这是很好的。 然后做一个E。
I think. Yeah, that's good. And then do an E.
实际上,你可以控制它 通过做E -Y 确保它直接挤压
And actually, you can control it by doing E-Y to make sure it extrudes directly
倒着
backwards.
好吧,这就是我的背包。
Okay, so that's my backpack.
还有一件事,到目前为止,我没有做 任何储蓄,这是超级,超级
And one thing, so far I've not done any saving whatsoever, and that's super, super
因为你会做很多,很多,很多事情, 然后你会尝试
dangerous because you will have done many, many, many things, and then you will try
做一个渲染, 你的电脑会崩溃, 你会失去一切。
to do a render, and your computer will crash, and you'll lose everything.
故别忘救. 所以控制 + S 要保存。 开始了
So don't forget to save. So Control + S to save. And here we go.
接下来,我们约70%在那里。 我们要创造一些腿。
Next, we're about 70% there. We're going to create some legs.
我将回到顶点选择模式 选择一个顶点, 通常在哪里
I'm going to go back to vertex select mode, select a vertex here, generally where
腿会是。 击X删除并击出面孔. 对不起
the legs are going to be. Hit X to delete and hit faces. Oops, sorry.
不,我必须... 对不起,让我们做三个。
No, I need to... Sorry, let's do three.
对于面部选择,请选择这四个方块。
For face select, select these four squares.
我要击打X删除和面孔, 我得到一个洞的腿去
I'm going to hit X to delete and faces, and I get a hole where the legs are going
成为。
to be.
点击 2 进行边缘选择 。 这里有一个新特点。
Hit two to do edge select. And here's a new feature.
我可以去,我可以选择一个边 一次,持有S,Shift键
I can go, and I can select one edge at a time, holding the S, the Shift key to
选择此腿周围产生环绕的所有边缘。
select all of the edges that generates the loop around this leg.
或者快捷键是击中阿尔特键.
Or the shortcut key is to hit the Alt key.
我相信一个Mac, 这是选择的关键,我想。
I believe on a Mac, that's the Option key, I think.
你们没有阿尔特 你们有选择
You guys don't have Alt, you have Option.
如果我按下阿尔特键 然后选择一个边缘,它就会自动
If I hold down the Alt key and then select one of the edges, it automatically
为您选择整个循环。 所以,这是一个真正, 真的非常好的时间保护
selects the entire loop for you. So this is a really, really good time-saver for
你们 他的腿有点...
you. And the guy's legs are a little bit...
圆融.
It's round.
我是不是该这么做?
Should I do this or should I not?
对 这是一点点
Yeah. This is a little bit of
高级技术,但我还是会告诉你。
advanced technique, but I will show you anyway.
在顶部,你有一些菜单, Mesh, Transform, To Sphere。
Up at the top here, you have a selection of menus, Mesh, Transform, To Sphere.
哦,孩子,为什么我得到了一切?
And ooh, boy, why am I getting everything?
好吧,比例编辑还在, 所以它影响了一切。
Okay, proportional editing is still on, so it's affecting everything.
我想做的是 我们中间的腿是圆的
What I want to do is the legs of the Among Us character is round.
现在,如果我把这个挤出来, 它会创造一个非常平方的腿, 但我
And right now, if I extrude this, it's going to create a very square leg, but I
要一条圆腿。 因此,梅什,变形,球。
want a round leg. So Mesh, Transform, To Sphere.
当我左右移动我的老鼠, 它使这个洞多一点
And when I move my mouse left and right, it makes that hole a little bit more
圆. 好吗? 现在你可以看到它从长方形变成圆形
round. Okay? So now you can see it's gone from a rectangular shape to a round
形状。
shape.
好吗? 现在我们要再向下进行一次挤压。
Okay? And now we're going to do another extrusion straight downwards.
所以,E,Z,去直下, 使它相当长,像这样,
So E, Z, to go straight down, make it pretty long, like that, and
你会明白为什么以后。 现在我要这个选定的区域,这个选定的边缘
you'll understand why later. Now I want this selected zone, this selected edge
与Z飞机平行 与我工作的表面平行
to be parallel to the Z plane, to the surface of my work
飞机 一个快捷键是按Z方向,零,
plane. A shortcut key for that is to scale in the Z direction, zero,
它会平整一切 再来一次
and it flattens out everything. One more time.
S,Z,0将采取对角集
S, Z, zero will take a diagonal set of
点和扁平它。 好吗? 不错的快捷键。
points and flatten it out. Okay? Nice shortcut key.
所以现在这里地势平坦
So now it's nice and flat to the bottom here.
你有一个洞, 如果你想填满这个洞, 你打F换脸,它
And you've got a hole, and if you want to fill the hole, you hit F for face, and it
补入洞中.
fills in the hole.
腿太长了,所以我要和G,Z一起把事情搞大
The legs are a little bit too long, so I'm going to move this up with G, Z, bring
像这样 现在,我的角色 已经创造了。
it up to like this. And now my Among Us character has now been created.
其实,他看起来太像豆子了 我想让这个部分一点点
Actually, he looks too much like a bean, and I want to make this part a little bit
更直,所以我可以增加一些额外的, 另一层循环在这里。
more straight, so I can add some extra, another loop at this level here.
为了在Blender中添加循环或循环剪切,您要进行控制+R,您可以添加
And to add loops or a loop cut in Blender, you do Control + R, and you can add
此位置的另一个循环 。 如果滚动鼠标,可以添加额外的循环.
another loop in this position. If you roll your mouse, you can add extra loops.
我只需要一个, 所以我要做这个点击, 现在我有一个额外的循环。
I only need one, so I'm going to do this click, and now I have an extra loop.
随着比例编辑的开启,
And with proportional editing turned on,
将移其下. G, Z. 我的圆圈很大
I'm going to move it down. G, Z. And my circle is very big.
我想改变影响到这么多。
I want to change the influence to about that much.
现在我可以把它移动下来, 它有一点点 -- 我可以改变形状
And now I can move it down, and it has a little bit-- I can change the shape a
一点点。 好吧,像这样。 这对我来说更...
little bit. Okay, like that. That to me looks a lot more...
你觉得怎么样,蒂娜? 这对我们来说是美丽的吗?
What do you think, Tina? Is that pretty Among Us to you?
是啊,你擅长吗? 好吧,回来
Yeah, you're good with that? Okay, back to
对象模式。 今又想道:"天,真难看. 它是如此的块。
object mode. Now you're thinking, "Oh my God, it's so ugly. It's so blocky.
这不好玩". 这就是修饰者的魔力再次出现的地方.
It's not interesting." So here's where the magic of modifiers comes in again.
第一件事,你可以只是 右鼠点击和去Shade,
The first thing you can do is you can just simply right mouse click and go Shade,
顺畅. 它比以前好一点。
Smooth. And it sort of makes it a little bit better than it was before.
却不善. 情况不妙,我要撤销它
But it's not good. It's not good, and I'm going to undo that.
不好 因为没有足够几何来创造光滑
It's not good because there's not enough geometry for this thing to create smooth
表面。 所以,现在我们要做 子分区表面一次 加一些
surfaces. So now we're going to do subdivision surface one more time to add some
额外的几何。 因此添加修改器,生成子分区表面,以及
extra geometry. So Add Modifier, Generate Subdivision Surface, and
看,看起来好多了
it's, see, already looking a lot better.
我要让这个二级 让它变得非常光滑
I'm going to make this level two to make it super smooth.
现在当我... 你仍然能看到这里的方块
And now when I-- you can still see squares here.
如果我是对的... 实际上,在我这样做之前, 我需要添加颜色。
If I right-- Actually, before I do that, I need to add colors.
现在,用更少的东西来选择, 我要在这件事情上添加颜色。
Now with fewer things to select, I'm going to add colors to this thing.
好吧,让我们去颜色预览模式。 红球. 我时间如何?
All right, so let's go to color preview mode. Red ball. How am I doing on time?
好吧,我仍然在一小时之内,我想。
Okay, I'm still within the hour, I think.
好吧,所以我们去纽。 我要叫这个物质的身体。
Okay, so we go to New. I'm going to call this material body.
蒂娜,你最喜欢什么颜色?
And Tina, what's your favorite color?
你最喜欢什么角色?
What's your favorite Among Us character?
红的
The red one.
红一. 好,我要把它弄红了 好吧,我们走。
Red one. Okay, so I'm going to make it red. All right.
但是,他的脸板是不同的颜色。
But then, his face plate is a different color.
因此,我们必须增加一个新的材料, 我们要叫这个面板。
So we have to add a new material, and we're going to call this one face plate.
脸
Face.
好吧,我觉得它有点白, 但我要让它有点粗鲁
Okay, and I think it's kind of white, but I'm going to make it a little bit bluish
因为这是我想做的。 好吧,有点粗糙。
because that's what I want to do. Okay, a little bit bluish.
还有
And
像那样,蓝白色。 好吧,所以如果你记得, 我们只需要进入编辑
like that, blue-white. All right, so if you remember, we just have to get into edit
模式。
mode.
脸部选择, 我会选择这些表面, 按住Shift键,
Face select, and I'm going to select these surfaces, hold down the Shift key,
在此选择所有其他表面。
select all of the other surfaces here.
现在去选择一张脸色并指定它。 现在我有一个白色的面板。
And now go select a face color and assign it. And now I got a white face plate.
好了,现在完成了,对象模式, 回到子分区表面,
Okay, now with that's done, object mode, go back to subdivision surface,
生成子分区表面,进行二级视图。
generate subdivision surface, do a viewport level two.
摆 你还是能看到里面的小广场
Okay. You can still see little squares inside here.
您可以点击鼠标右键选择阴影平滑 。
You can right mouse click and choose Shade Smooth.
而现在他完全性格平滑.
And now he's completely sexily smooth.
好吧,所以另一个事情 个性化它, 让它一点点你自己,我们
Okay, so another thing to personalize it, to make it a little bit more your own, we
甚至可以进去做点装饰,对不对?
can even go in there and do a little bit more decoration on this, right?
一旦你对一个人这样做,我们会得到, 我向你保证,你是
Once you do this on a human being, which we'll get to, I promise you that you're
我们今天要做一个人类的阿凡达, 我们将在第二小时完成。
going to make a human avatar today, and we'll do that in the second hour.
但让我教你怎么做
But let me show you how to do some
这东西上的微装饰。 这和我们以前加颜色的一样
micro decorations on this thing. It's the same technique as we used to add colors
对事物。 ┮и璶秈
to things. So we're going to go in here.
让我们创造第三个颜色, 我们要叫这个
Let's create a third color, and we're going to call this
装饰。
decoration.
我要让它变暗灰色
And I'm going to make it dark gray
为了我的装饰,好吗? 比如,我想把眼睛和嘴放在我身上
for my decoration, okay? And for instance, I want to put eyes and a mouth onto my
这家伙。 所以按下Tab键 我需要应用我的分支
guy. So hitting the Tab key, I need to apply my subdivision.
所以我需要回到修饰器 应用我的分支 回到Tab键
So I need to go back to modifier, apply my subdivisions, go back to the Tab key to
进来 现在,我可以选择,
get in here. Now I can select,
脸部选择3,脸部选择增加这两个, 也许,是的。
face select three, face select add these two, and maybe, yeah.
然后回到我的颜色,分配。 现在我有眼睛了
And then go back to my color, assign. Now I have eyes.
不 我不喜欢这样 让我们走近。 这里怎么样?
Nope, I don't like the position of that. Let's go closer. How about here?
指派 好吧,现在我有眼睛了。 砛и赣弧羘
Assign. Okay, now I have eyes. Maybe let's give it a mouth, too.
摆 然后为了更好玩,我们可以到后面去。
Okay. And then to make it even more fun, we can go to the back here.
我要用脸色,因为
I'm going to use a face color because it's
简单点 颜色不错 我要把一些符号放在后面。
easier. It's a nice color. And I'm going to put some symbol on the back.
实际上 回到我的修饰者那里 也应用镜子修饰者
Actually, and go back to my modifier and apply the mirror modifier as well.
既然我不再改变物体了 回到塔布那里
Since I'm not going to change the object anymore, go back to Tab,
我要在这里放个设计 开始吧
and I'm going to put a design here. Let's do
这个
this.
移动。
Shift.
那应该是一颗心。
That was supposed to be a heart.
我对艺术作品很不好 摆 这看起来像心脏吗?
I'm terrible at this bit art stuff. Okay. Does that look like a heart?
有点像一颗心脏 我要称之为心脏。
It kind of looks like a heart. I'm going to call that a heart.
好吧,然后到我的材料,脸,分配。 好吧,然后塔布。
All right, and then go to my materials, face, assign. All right, and then Tab.
所以现在你的人有一个脸, 背面有一个心脏符号, 你可以装饰它
So now your guy has a face, has a heart symbol on the back, and you can decorate it
让你心满意足
to your heart's content
好吧,我会做增量储蓄,
Okay, I'm going to do incremental save,
并添加我的目标。
and add my object.
摆 所以,这是一个小时了。 我在时间管理上表现不错
Okay. So that's one hour gone. I did pretty good on time management.
目前情况如何? 有什么问题我能回答吗?
How are we so far? Any questions that I can answer at the moment?
谢谢你,以斯拉,谢谢你
Thank you, Ezra, for the
审定。
validation.
有时候我觉得自己在自言自语
Sometimes I feel like I'm talking to myself.
好吧,这样的话,请继续休息5分钟或10分钟,然后
Okay, so with that, go ahead and take a 5-minute break or 10-minute break, and then
我们会回来的, 和我们的工作 制MakeHuman类。
we'll come back, and we'll work on Make Human.
因此,在中间,让我们做 10分钟, 以及从现在到那时, 我其实
So in between, let's make it 10 minutes, and between now and then, I would actually
比如,如果可能的话,让你打开你的Blender 因为很多我要去
like, if possible, for you to open your Blender because a lot of what I'm going to
显示一个设置 。 如何在Blender内部安装人,然后
show you is a settings thing. How to install Make Human inside of Blender, so then
你可以做你自己的东西。 而这个你可以随从 非常,非常容易,
you can make your own thing. And this one you can follow along very, very easily,
好吗? 因此,10分钟,请安装 Blender,最新版本, 我们将
okay? So 10 minutes, please install Blender, the latest version, and we will
之后继续,好吗? 好吧,冷静。
resume afterwards, okay? All right, cool.
林戈,对不起
Ringo, sorry,
能问个问题吗?
is it possible to ask a question?
5块,请说
$5. Yes, go ahead.
我有Mac 但我试着安装最新版本 它没有允许我。
I have Mac, but I tried to install the latest version. It didn't allow me.
所以我安装了第三次最新。
So I installed the third latest.
摆 什么样的版本?
Okay. What version is it?
4.3 (中文(简体) ).
4.3.
是吗?
Oh, really?
对 它不允许。
Yeah. It didn't allow.
真让人惊讶 好吧,让我看看发生了什么。
That's surprising. Okay, let me see what's going on.
这是Mac问题还是Blender问题?
Is that a Mac problem or a Blender problem?
让我分享一个屏幕,我们可以一起研究这个问题。
Let me share screen, and we can take a look at this issue together.
你看到我的下载屏幕了吗? 对 摆 下载 Blender 。 摆
Are you seeing my download screen? Yes. Okay. Download Blender. Okay.
麦克OS.
Mac OS.
你绝对...
You definitely-
对 我的麦克是文图拉
Yeah. My Mac is Ventura
应该是1.3
1.3, I think.
摆
Okay.
对 文图拉 硅酮对我的iMac不起作用
Yeah, Ventura, and the silicone doesn't work on my iMac.
摆
Okay.
对
Yeah.
但这是个大问题吗? 对
But is it a big problem? Yeah.
不,这不应该是一个问题,但我不知道。 问题是这个。
No, it should not be a problem, but I don't know. The issue is this.
Blender 经常更新,每次更新时,都会更新一些功能:
Blender updates all the time, and every time it updates, some functionality of
它在之前的版本中被使用过,在新版本中已不再以同样的方式工作
it, which was used in a previous version, no longer works the same way in the new
版本。 所以,我只是不想 在一个情况,你喜欢, "为什么
version. So I just don't want to be in a situation where you're like, "How come it
难道我的Blender不起作用?" 所以,我只是不知道什么会 和不会工作,但
doesn't work on my Blender?" So I just don't know what will and will not work, but
让我们用我们所能做的。 好吗?
let's just work with what we can work with. Okay?
摆 非常感谢 对
Okay. Thank you so much. Yes.
试问如何是道.
Let's see what we can do.
对
Mm-hmm.
我不是麦克人 所以我会尽力回答麦克的问题
I'm not a Mac guy at all, so I will do my best to answer Mac questions, but I'm a
编码 -
coding-
是的,我是如此陌生 编码或任何东西,所以
Yes, and I'm so alien to coding or anything, so
没关系
That's okay.
对
So, yeah.
别着急 跟着我,在法布学院结束时,你永远不会
Don't worry about it. You stick with me, by the end of Fab Academy, you're never
永远不会再说一遍。 你会感觉像超级。
going to ever say that again. You're going to be feeling like super.
摆 非常感谢 摆 再见
Okay. Thank you so much. Okay. See you.
好吧,休息十分钟
Okay. 10-minute break.
摆
Okay.
已经10分钟了吗? 我不知道,我还不知道
Has it been 10 minutes? I have no idea.
摆 大家都回来了吗?
Okay. Is everybody back?
大部分吗? 让我看看。 我看看能不能看见每个人的脸
Mostly? Let me see. Let me see if I can see everybody's faces.
好吧,我们走。 运行,运行,运行到你的座位。 该走了
All right. Run, run, run to your seat. It's time to get going.
谢谢你,丽贝卡。
Thank you, Rebecca.
你从哪里来,丽贝卡? 我喜欢你的形象
Where are you from, Rebecca? I love your image.
丽贝卡·FL.
Rebecca FL.
你从哪里来?
Where are you from?
顿 我来自西班牙
Hi. I'm from Spain-
西班牙语。
Spain.
但我住在布鲁塞尔 对
But I live in Brussels. Yes.
但你住在布鲁塞尔? 摆
But you live in Brussels? Okay.
对
Yes.
在西班牙的哪个地方?
Where in Spain?
我没有相机,对不起。
And I don't have a camera, I'm sorry.
没关系
That's okay.
我把我的笔记本电脑关了
I had put my laptop closed.
你从西班牙来?
Where in Spain are you from?
我来自北部,来自加利西亚。
I'm from the north, from Galicia.
加利西亚. 一定是在莱昂附近吗,努里亚?
Galicia. That must be somewhere near Leon, Nuria?
是的,它就在大西洋旁边
Yes, it's next to the Atlantic Ocean.
摆 摆 我女儿现在在塞戈维亚上学
Okay. Okay. My daughter is going to school in Segovia right now.
珃 她喜欢吗?
Wow. Is she liking it?
我觉得她太喜欢了
She loves it a little bit too much, I think.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
我期待一个西班牙男友 很快会在日本出现
I'm expecting a Spanish boyfriend to show up in Japan one of these days soon.
这么说吧
Let's put it that way.
摆 很不错 好吧,伟大的。 让我看看。 我们在看什么?
Okay. Very nice. Okay, great. Let's see. What are we looking at?
一个空白的谷歌屏幕。 MakeHuman。 让我们去那里。
A blank Google screen. MakeHuman. Let's go there.
你们中有多少人曾经使用过MakeHuman?
How many of you have used MakeHuman before?
一个
One.
好吧,所以MakeHuman是惊人的
Okay, so MakeHuman is an amazing
应用程序,它允许您制作这样的外观 。
application that allows you to make avatars like this.
所以,它有一个... 我不知道这是互联网还是应用程序
So, it has a... I don't know if this is internet-based or it's an app.
我不确定,我还不知道 我认为这是一个安装的应用程序。
I'm not sure. I think it's an installed app.
但你可以进去 你可以做改变性别 年龄之类的事
But you can get in there, and you can do things like change the gender, age,
肌肉,等等 来获得你想要的角色。
muscle, so on and so forth to get the character that you want.
所以,正如我承诺的, 你将能够生成自己的阿凡达。
So, as I promised, you're going to be able to generate your own avatar.
然后用所有的Blender模型技术 我刚刚给你看,你可以
And then with all of those blender modeling techniques I just showed you, you can
添加各种不同的特性。
add all kinds of different features.
例如,如果你想添加一个额外的手臂,或者你想有一个机器人
For instance, if you want to add an extra arm or if you want to have a cyborg
挤出头部,你也可以这样做。
extrusion pop out of the head, you can do that as well.
这就是为什么我们花时间 制造香水瓶和我们之中
So that's why we spent that time making the perfume bottle and the Among Us
性格,因为我要你明白 如何操纵事物。
character, because I want you to understand how to manipulate things.
我刚刚意识到我们上厕所的时候 我没有停止录音
I just realized I didn't stop the recording while we went to the bathroom.
好吧,好吧,我会确保 切断这一点。
Okay, well, I'll make sure to cut that out.
总之,这里的奇妙之处是 这个很棒的软件有一个
Anyway, the wonderful thing here is that this awesome software has a
直接的Blender整合, 这意味着你可以做所有这些美妙的 MakeHuman
direct blender integration, which means you can do all of these wonderful MakeHuman
直接在Blender中,而不使用两个不同的软件。
things directly in Blender and without using two different softwares.
你通过到这里的MPFB。
And you do that by going here to MPFB.
我认为这代表了MakeHuman为Blender做点什么。 这代表什么?
And I think it stands for MakeHuman something for Blender. What does it stand for?
MakeHuman。 总之,你点击这个,
MakeHuman. Anyway, you go click on this,
MPFB (英语).
MPFB.
是啊,还好。 你可以去MPFB下载。
Yeah, okay. And you can go to MPFB download.
且向甚么处得. 好吧,所以是啊,不是一个伟大的网站。
And where you go to get it. Okay, so yeah, not a great website.
初明镜即随所求处.
Primary Mirror is where you want to go.
这里写着,你通常在这里下载MPFB2.
So it says here, this is where you usually download MPFB2.
我想这是最新版本了 所以,我想,你点击 某处在这里?
I guess that's the newest version. So I think, do you click somewhere here?
你从哪里得到这个?
Where can you get this?
也许在这里? 我不知道. 对不起
Maybe here? I don't know. I'm sorry.
下载。
Downloads.
CMP下载. 在甚么处. 这里。 好吧,一旦我找到它, 我会送你
CMP downloads. Where is it? Here. Okay, once I find it, I'm going to send you
链接。
the link.
哪里? 哪里来的? MPFB下载. 我在这里。
Where? MPFB downloads. I'm here.
我在Blender做过 我直接从Blender那里放的
I did it in Blender. I just put it from Blender directly.
摆 但我要这样做 因为你要下载更多
Okay. But I want to do it this way because you're going to have to download more
不仅仅是程序本身。 摆
than just the program itself. Okay.
是啊,让我们在Blender做, 然后我们回来这里做其他的事情。
Yeah, let's do it in Blender, and then we'll come back here for other things.
好吧,所以回到Blender。
Okay, so back to Blender.
我要把我的小朋友藏在这里
I'm going to hide my little friend here.
好,所以闪亮
Okay, so Blender
作为它自己的软件是强大的, 但你可以增加额外的功能,
is powerful as its own software, but you can add extra functionalities to it,
加进会给它更多它能...
add-ons that will give it additional things that it can...
因为它是一个开源软件,其他开发者也创造了额外的功能
Because it's an open-source software, other developers have created extra features
你可以选择下载 并添加到您的东西, 你这样做
to it that you can choose to download and add to your thing, and you do that by
去编辑菜单,首选项,好吗? 在首选项中,你可以看到添加。
going to the Edit menu, Preferences, okay? And in Preferences, you see Add-ons.
好吗? 如果你去加注 和你去在这里和打 MPFB,它应该
Okay? If you go to add-ons and you go up here and type MPFB, it should
出现. 如果它不出现,去Get Extensions,它高于加农,和
show up. If it doesn't show up, go to Get Extensions, which is above Add-ons, and
类型 MPFB。
type MPFB.
好吧,所以你们现在这样做 告诉我,如果你能找到它,
All right, so you guys do that right now and tell me if you're able to find it,
因为我的车已经安装好了
because mine is already installed.
谁说你直接安装在Blender?
Who was it that said you installed directly in Blender?
蒂娜 蒂娜 蒂娜 蒂娜 蒂娜 好吧,你这样做 通过扩展或添加?
Tina. Okay, did you do it through Extensions or Add-ons?
我得到了它通过Get扩展。
I got it through Get Extensions.
扩展 摆
Extensions. Okay.
我有Blender2.1版,我想是的。
I have Blender version 2.1, I think it was.
如果你无法在扩展中找到它, 这可能是因为你不是
If you're not able to find it in Extensions, it might be because you are not
允许Blender搜索互联网, 你允许通过去系统,
allowing Blender to search the internet, and you allow that by going to System,
还有这里 设有网络,内容为"Allow在线访问". 你想让
and here. There's a network, and it says, "Allow online access." You want to make
肯定查过了 如果选中的话, 当你去扩展和
sure that's checked. If that's checked, then whenever you go to Extensions and
它应该能找到它 好吗?
search for anything, it should be able to find it, okay?
亲爱的Rico 你能再展示一次吗?
Dear Rico, can you please show one more time?
我打开了优惠,但是
I opened the Preferences, but
我不知道我该...
I'm not sure what I should-
摆 所以在中间,你应该看到Add -ons, 而就在上面...
Okay. So in the middle, you should see Add-ons, and right above that-
补上. 对
Add-ons. Mm-hmm
...你应该看看《获得扩展》
... you should see Get Extensions.
而在"Get扩展"(Get Extensions)中,最上面的中心有一个搜索菜单.
And in Get Extensions, there's a search menu at the very top center.
对
Mm-hmm.
如果您输入了 MPFB , 您应该能找到
If you type MPFB there, you should be able to find
MakeHuman
the MakeHuman
加号 我想它一到就应该有一个安装按钮
add-on. And I think there should be an Install button next to it once it arrives.
有没有人无法通过Blender找到MPFB?
Is anyone having trouble finding MPFB via Blender?
如果你是,举起手来,还是不动,告诉我。 哦,不错。
If you are, raise your hand or unmute and let me know. Oh, good.
每个人都很好。 好吧,我们走。
Everybody's good on that. All right.
所以一旦MPFB安装在你的电脑上
So once MPFB is installed on your computer,
检查旁边的复选框。
in my case, make sure that the checkbox next to it is checked.
如果是这样,它不会被激活.
If it's like this, it's not being activated.
务必检查好才能激活
Make sure that it's checked so that it's activated.
因为一旦它被激活 你就回到...
Because once it's activated, you come back to the...
顺便说一句,大家都赶上了吗? 大家都追上来了? 对 摆
By the way, is everybody caught up? Everybody's caught up? Yeah. Okay.
如果你击中了N键, 边菜单就会出现, 你会看到, MPFB 2. 0 是一个
If you hit the N key, the side menu comes up, and you'll see that MPFB 2.0 is one
以特性显示的选项。
of the options that shows up as a feature.
不错 好吧,我们走。 但在我们使用它之前 我们确实需要下载一些额外的东西
Good. All right. But before we use it, we do need to download some extra things,
回到MakeHuman网站
and here's where we need to go back to the MakeHuman website into
下载文件夹。 我们需要下载一些资产,对不对?
the Downloads folder. We need to download some assets, right?
因此,Blender MPFB 将允许您生成一个
So the Blender MPFB as it is will allow you to generate a
人,但你将无法增加 眼睛,头发,衣服或任何东西
human being, but you will not be able to add eyes or hair or clothing or anything
像这样 所以,这将是一个裸体的,没有眼球的人, 这是美丽的
like that. So it'll be a naked, eyeball-less human being, which is pretty
恐怖,你不希望这样。
terrifying, and you don't want that.
所以,让我们回到这里 确保我们得到一些额外的东西,以确保我们能
So, let's go back here and make sure we get some extra stuff to make sure we can
得到头发和类似的东西。 这是通过资产包完成的。
get hair and things like that. And that's done through asset packs here.
所以你点击资产包。 我要把连接在这里
So you click Asset Packs. I'm going to put the link to this here
进入聊天,如果我能找到聊天。 我的谈话呢? 这里。
into the chat if I can find the chat. Where's my chat? Here.
有人说你没看到我的电视机
Uh-oh, somebody said that you don't see my screencast.
对不起,我还没有看 聊天。
I'm sorry, I haven't been looking at the chat at all.
斯蒂芬妮,爱你的性格。 天啊,我本该在休息时这么做的
Stephanie, love your character. My God, I should have done this during the break.
这些命令是否有书面来源? 对
Is there written sources with these commands? Yes.
如果你谷歌Blender的捷径, 有很多很多这样的东西。
If you Google Blender shortcuts, there are lots and lots of these things.
我知道你已经找到了
I know you found it already.
摆
Okay.
好吧,这里是资产包。
All right, so here is the asset pack.
你真正需要的就是这里 创MakeHuman类系统的资产
The one that you really need is right here, MakeHuman System Asset.
请下载。 创MakeHuman类系统资产。
Please download that. MakeHuman System Assets.
好吧,所以如果我点击, 它会显示所有可爱的东西你得到
Okay, so if I click on that, it will show you all of the lovely things you get in
这批资产。 头发,耶。 眼睛,对了。
this asset pack. Hair, yay. Eyes, yay.
还有什么? 眉毛,对了。 这么多美好的事
What else do we have? Eyebrows, yay. So many wonderful things.
帽子,一些普通服装。
Hats, some generic clothing.
这些东西都会随之而来
All these things will come with this
MakeHuman系统成为资产。 摆 你知道吗?
Make Human system asset. Okay. You know what?
我可以在聊天时把这个链接发给你
I can send you this link as well in the chat.
摆 目前,我需要你 下载到您的下载文件夹和
Okay. For the time being, I need you to download this into your download folder and
不要取出来。 不要解开它,就放在那里。
do not extract it. Do not unzip it, just leave it there.
只要有一次你表现得更好, 那你可能会想要一些其他的东西。
And just for once you get better at this, then you might want some other things.
比如说你们可能想要姿势
Like for you guys, you might want poses, for instance.
这里有一些通用的姿势, 您可以下载您可能想要的
There are some generic poses here that you can download that you might want to be
能够使用。 所以,请继续,如果你想,你可以下载姿势。
able to use. So go ahead and if you want, you can download poses.
如果你对一般的发型不满意的话,这里还有一些额外的发型.
There's some extra hair here if you are dissatisfied with the generic hairstyles.
这个给你更多的发型,发色.
This one gives you more hairstyles, hair color.
总之,所有这些资产都可以给你 随便玩玩
Anyway, all these assets are available to you. Poke around and play with it.
现在,让我们回到Blender继续。
For now, let's go back to Blender and continue.
好吧,我们走。 所以,在我们做任何有趣的事情之前, 我们必须做一个
All right. So before we do any fun things, we have to do one
还有一件事是...
more other thing is-
对不起,快点...
Sorry, a quick-
对
Yeah
...关于下载的快速问题。
... a quick question about downloading.
它给我两个选项,镜子一或镜子二。 都好吗?
It gives me two options, mirror one or mirror two. Is both okay?
任何一个都很好 基本上,它是一个服务器在一个位置 相对于服务器在
Either one is fine. Basically, it's a server in one location versus a server in
另一个地点。 没关系
another location. Doesn't matter.
摆
Okay.
对 问得好
Yeah. Good question.
你从哪里来,伊兹?
Where are you from, Izzy?
我其实是英国人
I'm from England, actually.
摆 你现在在英国?
Okay. And you're in England right now?
不,其实我现在在阿姆斯特丹
No, actually I'm in Amsterdam right now.
哦,没关系。 你是阿姆斯特丹的英国人 阿姆斯特丹的英国人
Oh, okay. You're an Englishman in Amsterdam. English person in Amsterdam.
是的,非常喜欢。
Yes, very much.
很不错。
Very good.
好吧,我们走。 所以请
All right. So please,
再来一次,打N
one more time, hit N
在 Blender 中打开侧面板,您应该将 MPFB 作为标签。
in Blender to open up the side panel, and you should see MPFB as a tab.
点击那个标签,好吗? 你会看到一堆不同的
Click on that tab, okay? And you'll see a bunch of different
板在那个。 点击系统和资源。 不,不是系统和资源。
panels in that. Click on system and resource. No, not system and resources.
等一下,给我一秒钟。
Hold on, give me a second.
哦,不,它不在这里。 我们需要回去编辑首选项
Oh no, it's not here. We need to go back to edit preferences
并加入到你的MPFB这里。
and add-ons and go to your MPFB here.
在MPFB旁边,你可以看到一个右指箭头.
And next to MPFB, you see a right-pointing arrow.
点击它来扩展 MPFB, 这样你就可以看到更多的它。
Click on that to expand MPFB, so you can see more of it.
关键是我们需要创造一条通往...
What's critical here is we need to create a path to...
你无法真正看到它, 但在这里它说,路径 MPFB 用户数据。
You can't really see it, but here it says, path to MPFB user data.
这个文件夹是用来安装和保存所有资产和东西的
This folder is where you're going to install and keep all of your assets and stuff
像这样,让MPFB的Blend知道 在那里寻找头发和衣服,
like that, so that MPFB for Blend will know to look there for hair and clothing and
你下载的那些东西 好吗? 所以你需要创造出来。
things like that that you've downloaded. Okay? So you need to create that.
我不知道怎么用Mac来做 所以,在Windows, 我会说,我会去我的
I'm not sure how to do it on a Mac. So on Windows, I would say I would go to my
Windows 探索器. 我会去像文件一样的地方 对吧?
Windows Explorer. I would go somewhere like Documents, right?
我会创建一个名为MPFB的文件夹. 所以我创造了一个已经叫MPF...
I would create a folder called MPFB. So I created one already called MPF...
对不起 我创造了一个叫做MPFB的数据。 好吗?
Oops, sorry. I created one already called MPFB data. Okay?
在 Windows 中,我会把鼠标点击这里并复制为路径以获取路径
In Windows, I would right mouse click here and copy as path to get the path
到那个文件夹,然后我会回到喜好,添加,
to that folder, and then I would go back to preferences, add-ons,
MPFB,MPFB用户数据的路径,并粘贴我的路径
MPFB, path to MPFB user data, and paste the path to my
文件夹在那个位置。
folder into that spot.
有人能帮我理解怎么用Mac做吗?
Anybody can help me to understand how to do that on Mac?
我……
I
认为您可以右键点击并说复制路径到文件夹 。
think you could make a right click and say copy path to a folder.
对 我不记得了
Mm. I don't remember.
垛
Um.
我认为,你必须正确点击该信息, 然后你可以看到路径和
I think that you have to right click that info, and then you can see the path and
然后复制粘贴。
then copy paste.
对不起,再来一次,艾琳
Sorry, one more time, Erin.
右键点击你的文件夹,然后得到信息, 然后它说在哪里,你
So right click on your folder and then get info, and then it says where, and you
有路径, 我认为你必须复制粘贴。
have the path, and this I think you have to copy paste.
好吧,完美无缺。 所以,当我在Windows上做的时候, 我的路径就会有引用
Okay, perfect. So, when I do it on Windows, my path comes with quotes on either
边 你需要删除引号,这样就
side. That you need to delete the quote marks so that it's just
我的驱动器C,用户,等等 和MPFB数据作为最后的事情。
my drive C, user, so on and so forth, and MPFB data as the final thing.
当它被设定在那里, 你需要去的左下侧
And when that's set in there, you need to go on the lower left-hand side of the
偏好窗口。 有一个汉堡图标。 确保你省省偏好。
preferences window. There's a hamburger icon. And make sure you save preferences.
这是关键,好吗?
This is critical, okay?
保存首选项 。 现在MPFB会知道这个文件夹在这里。
Save preferences. And now MPFB will know that this folder's here.
事实上,我认为我们需要关闭 Blender 并回来,为了这个
Actually, I think we need to shut down Blender and come back in, for this to be
理解得够清楚的 所以我现在就去做
well understood. So I'm going to go ahead and do that right now.
我要杀死Blender 并保存我的档案 并重新启动它。
I'm going to kill Blender and save my file and restart it again.
也许在Mac上是不需要的 因为你们...
Maybe on a Mac that's not required because you guys are...
这是一个更开明的PC. 好吧,我会回到辅导。
It's a more enlightened PC. Okay, and I'll go back to tutorial.
哦,不是这个文件。 哦,这不重要。
Oops, not this one file. Oh, it doesn't matter.
对不起,只有一个问题。 您必须输出文件夹中的拉链吗 ?
Sorry, just one question. Do you have to export the zip in the folder once it's in?
啊,还好。 接下来我教你怎么做 别做任何...
Ah, okay. So I'll show you how to do that next. Do not do any of...
你这样做在Blender。 我们现在就这么做 好吗?
You do that within Blender. So we'll do that exactly right now, okay?
好吧,如果你回到Blender, 再次,N键打开侧面板,
Okay, so if you're back in Blender, one more time, N key to open up the side panel,
点击MPFB, 现在我们要去...
click MPFB, and now we're going to...
有一个名为应用资产。
There's a panel called Apply Assets.
应用资产。
Apply Assets.
在"应用资产"(Application Deposits)中,有一个名为库设置的类别.
In Apply Assets, there's a category called Library Settings.
你要打开它。
You're going to open that.
在库设置的底部,它表示从zip文件中装入包.
At the bottom of library settings, it says load pack from zip file.
哦,首先,移动所有的东西 在您的 MPFB 数据文件夹。
Oh, first of all, move everything into your MPFB data folder.
如果您还没有这样做, 移动所有的东西到您的 MPFB 数据文件夹中去
If you haven't done that already, move everything into your MPFB data folder so
它知道如何去那里寻找东西。
that it knows how to go there to look for things.
里科,你说N键打开... N键是什么意思?
Rico, you said N key to open the... What does N key mean?
额...
Uh-
对不起 您键盘上的字母 N 。 所以这个侧面板消失了,好吗?
Sorry. The letter N on your keyboard. So this side panel here disappears, okay?
但如果我输入N,那封信... 哦,对不起,我的播音员 不再显示
But if I type the N, the letter... Oh, sorry, my screencast is not showing anymore
因为我关闭。 好吧,让我再做一次。
because I shut down. Okay, let me do that one more time.
对
Mm-hmm.
你看到了吗? 这些是我碰过的钥匙
You see here? These are the keys that I'm touching.
所以我打了N,侧面板打开了。 谓此义.
So I hit N and the side panel pops open. That's what that means.
对 当...
Uh-huh. When-
好吗? 在你右手边的标签中 应该有一个说
Okay? And amongst the tabs you have on the right-hand side, one of them should say
MPFB (英语).
MPFB.
对 摆 非常感谢 对
Yes. Okay. Thank you so much. Yes.
摆 当你选择它时, 有一个名为应用资产。
Okay. And when you select that, there's a panel called Apply Assets.
对 摆
Yes. Okay.
在“应用资产”中,您想要访问库设置。
In Apply Assets, you want to go to Library Settings.
对
Mm-hmm.
在库设置的底部,有一个来自zip文件的负载包.
In the bottom of library settings, there is a load pack from zip file.
所以,你将点击这个 然后去你的"制MakeHuman类"数据
So you're going to click on that and then go to your Make Human data
您所有的东西所在的文件夹 。
folder where all of your stuff is located.
MakeHuman数据文件夹
Make Human data folder
在这里,
here,
然后单击您刚刚选择的资产文件。 好吗?
and then click on that asset file that you just selected. Okay?
说MakeHuman系统 资产或什么的。
The one that says Make Human system assets or whatnot.
一旦你这样做, 所有的眼球和... 是的,伊兹。
Once you've done that, all of those eyeballs and... Yes, Izzy.
顿 对不起,我真的找不到它。
Hi. I'm sorry I really cannot find it.
啊,还好。
Ah, okay.
我可以按N键和...
I can press the N and the-
你为什么不分享屏幕?
Why don't you share screen?
一秒钟就好
One second will do.
继续分享屏幕 这样我就能看看你有什么
Go ahead and share screen so I can take a look at what you have.
对 一秒钟。
Yeah. One second.
摆 所以我在这里。 我按了N键
Okay. So I'm here. I pressed the N.
给我一秒钟。 还在装货
Give me a second. It's still loading for me.
瓳
Oh.
对
Yep.
这是与 N 点击。
This is with N clicked.
对 因为MPFB还没有被选中,所以没有出现.
Yep. It's not showing up because MPFB has not been selected.
您需要编辑 。 转到编辑菜单。
You need to go to edit. Go to the edit menu.
对
Uh-huh.
首选项。
Preferences.
一秒钟。
One second.
是吗?
Hmm.
摆 补上.
Okay. Add-ons.
补上. 对
Add-ons. Mm-hmm.
(原始内容存档于2018-09-26). MPF. 进入顶端搜索并输入 MPFB 。
MPF. Go to the search at the top and type MPFB.
好的，你还没有……MPFB。B 就是字母 B。
Okay, you haven't... MPFB. B like boy.
好吧,你还没有安装它。 故说. 现在去得到扩展。
Okay, you haven't installed it. That's why. Now go to get extensions.
摆
Okay.
然后点击允许在线访问。
Ah, and then click allow online access.
摆 然后在这里, 类型 MPFB。
Okay. And then in here, type MPFB.
就像男孩一样
B like boy,
点击 Enter。
and hit Enter.
没有远程数据 。 远程仓库 。 这可能是你的系统。
Remote data unavailable. Remote repository. It might be your system.
好吧,我们可以去系统?
Okay, can we go to System?
摆
Okay.
好吧,允许在线访问开始。 获取扩展。 是吗?
And okay, Allow Online Access is on. Get Extensions. Hmm.
摆 我们要从现场直接安装到这里
Okay. This is where we're going to need to install it directly from the site
它本身。 你能...
itself. Can you-
我已经做了。 你是说《MakeHuman》? 我已经做了。
I already did that. You mean about the MakeHuman? I already did this.
你下载了资产包,对吧?
You downloaded the asset pack, right?
对 还有...
Yes. And also,
我下载了资产包 还有这个应用程序 应用软件.
I downloaded the asset pack and also this app. The app.
是吗?
You did?
(原始内容存档于2017-03-27). The MPFB. 摆
The MPFB. Okay.
对
Right.
你能去网站 展示你下载的东西吗?
Can you go to the website and show me what you downloaded?
单 所以我下载了资产包。
One sec. So I downloaded the asset pack.
对
Uh-huh.
后来我还下载了最新的一个。
And then I also downloaded the most recent one here.
哦,伟大的。 不错 好吧,完美无缺。
Oh, great. Perfect. Okay, perfect.
但我有这个分开的...
But I have this separate-
好吧,让我们安装它。 让我们去 -
Okay, so let's install it. Let's go to-
比如申请?
Like an application?
是的,让我们去...
Yeah, let's go to...
加点?
Add-ons?
MPFB为Blender版本. 故曰加进. 你能在这里补充吗?
MPFB is the Blender version. So let's go to add-ons. Can you go to add-ons here?
对
Yeah.
好的，
Okay,
伟大的。 而去此降点箭.
great. And go this down-pointing arrow.
我要你去右侧的箭头
I want you to go to down-pointing arrow over here on the right side.
摆 对
Okay. Yep.
从磁盘上安装。
And install from disk.
好吧,完美无缺。 MakeHuman?
Okay, perfect. MakeHuman?
额...
Uh-
所以,我安装在那里?
So I install from there?
您能查看下载文件夹吗 ?
Can you look in your downloads folder?
是否有Make Human社区?
Is there a MakeHuman community?
我怀疑是不是这样
I wonder if that's it.
那是我作为第一页下载的 因为我...
That was what I downloaded as that first page, because I-
试试看 试试看,然后从磁盘上安装,看看它是否有效。
Try that. Try that one, and hit install from disk and see if it works.
摆
Okay.
没有。 摆
Nope. Okay.
是吗?
No?
等我一下 我试着找出你该写什么档案
Give me a second here while I try to figure out what file you're supposed to
下载。
download.
摆
Okay.
视窗.
Windows.
对,MPFB 如我所说,有两件事。
Yeah, MPFB. There are two things, as I mentioned.
有Make Human的应用软件,你运行在你的桌面上,还有Make Human
There's the MakeHuman app, which you run on your desktop, and there's a MakeHuman
Blender的加载。 我们想要的是下载加载,
add-on for Blender. What we want is to download the add-on,
但我很难找到它在哪里。
but I'm struggling to find where that is.
资产包。 给我一点时间 对不起,这需要很长时间。
Asset packs. Give me a second here. I'm sorry, it's taking a long time.
是吗? 乃劝汝作么生. 好吧,这样吧
Hmm. It's telling you to do it. Okay, so
其他人,我想,已经成功地安装了Make Human,对不对?
everybody else, I'm assuming, has successfully installed MakeHuman, right?
哪里是我的... ... 是谁?
Where is my...
哦,这里。 闲聊 摆
Oh, here. Chat. Okay.
对不起,只有一个问题。 我安装了Make Human, 但我不知道是什么
Sorry, just one question. I installed MakeHuman, but I don't know which
资产,我们应该
assets we should
或者我们应该从Blender开始 我不知道.
transfer, or if we should just start with Blender. I don't know.
摆 接下来让我来处理你的问题
Okay. So let me handle your question next.
伊兹,在链接中...
Izzy, in the link-
当然
Sure
...有一个网站,你需要去, 有一个按钮叫Get
... there's a website that you need to go to, and there's a button called Get
在那页上添加 你为什么不去那里?
Add-On on that page. Why don't you go there?
向下滚. 右侧, 获得 Add -On, 点击。
Scroll down. Right side, Get Add-On, click that.
然后拖进Blender?
And then drag and drop into Blender?
拖到Blender那里去
Drag and drop into Blender.
这应该可行。
That should work.
瓳
Oh.
它不见了。
It disappeared.
再试一次
Try it again.
对
Yeah.
如果你们...
If you-
拖到3D视图窗口。
Drag it and drop it into the 3D viewport window.
对 单 摆
Yeah. One sec. Ah.
开始了
There we go.
对不起,等一下。
Sorry, one second.
别担心 我知道,我记得 做这个真是噩梦
No worries. I know. It's a nightmare trying to do this-
有个...
There's a-
...在实时。
... in real-time.
开始了
There we go.
摆
Okay.
"发现仓库. 这个扩展..." 摆
"Repository found. This extension..." Okay.
一秒钟。 它说,"发现的仓库没有在远程
One second. It said, "Repository found was not found in a remote
仓库". 对
repository." Yeah.
这部分的寄存器和比对... 检查这部分... 是吗?
This part of the repository and compat... Check that this part... Hmm.
不是百分之百的肯定。 让我们确保它没有成功安装。
Not 100% sure. Let's just make sure that it didn't successfully install.
之后我们可能会调试这个 我得去调查一下
And we might have to debug this afterwards. I'm going to have to look into this.
对
Mm-hmm.
好吧,所以继续 继续你的喜好。
Okay, so go ahead and go into your preferences again.
编辑、 首选项、 添加内容, 让我们看看
Edit, Preferences, Add-ons, and let's see if
MPFB已经在里面了
MPFB is already in there.
这是... 没有
It's... Yeah. No.
您可以在顶端输入 MPFB 吗 ?
Can you type MPFB at the top?
没有 瓳
No. Huh.
摆 伊兹,我待会再找你
Okay. Izzy, I'm going to have to come back to you later on.
我有点好奇...
I'm a little bit curious-
对
Yeah
...关于为什么会这样 好吧,我们走。
... as to why this is happening. All right.
那么另一个问题来自谁?
So then the other question came from who?
对不起 它来自我。
Sorry. It came from me.
嗨,维达 摆
Hi, Vida. Okay.
顿
Hi.
你需要的宝藏... 我将分享屏幕。
The asset pack that you need to... I'm going to share screen.
好吧,我们走。 我们在这里看什么?
All right. What are we looking at here?
摆 所以,在MPFB的下载下,你想要去资产包,这就是
Okay. So under MPFB downloads, you want to go to Asset Packs, which is
在这里。
here.
现在唯一需要安装的是这个
And out of Asset Packs, the only one right now that you need to install is this one
在这里,MakeHuman系统资产。
here, MakeHuman System Assets.
对
Mm-hmm.
所以,对,我在资产部分, 然后MakeHuman -
So, right, I'm in the assets part, and then MakeHuman-
什么资产的一部分? 布莱德?
Assets part of what? Blender?
点击你共享的链接
Yeah, just click on the link that you shared.
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
不过,所以...
But, so-
你为什么不分享你的屏幕? 让我们这样做,所以我至少可以看到
Why don't you share your screen? Let's do it this way, so I can at least see what
你这样做。
you're doing.
摆 但我不知道怎样... 等等,对不起。 对不起
Okay. But I don't know how to... Wait, sorry. I'm sorry.
顿
Hi.
我能说点什么吗?
Can I say something?
对
Yeah.
也许是因为我也很困惑 但有米罗和米罗
Maybe it's because, I was confused too, but that there is the Miro one and the Miro
您必须下载两个链接。 也许这就是问题所在?
two link you have to download from. Maybe that's the problem?
对
Mm.
亦不见. Izzy收到的错误信息似乎表明
I don't think so. The error message that Izzy got seems to indicate that it's a
版本不兼容问题。
version incompatibility issue.
我在想丽塔的问题
I was thinking of Rita's problem.
哦,丽塔的问题。 摆
Oh, Rita's problem. Okay.
单单
Wait.
你能分享屏幕吗?
Are you able to share screen?
对 也许吧 对 摆 所以我就在这里。
Yeah. Probably. Yeah. Okay. So I just go here.
这是法布学院的基本技能.
This is a fundamental Fab Academy skill.
你得好好干这个
You're going to need to be really good at this.
我怎么分享屏幕? 我从来没有共享过屏幕。
How do I share screens? I never shared a screen before.
下方工具栏有一个共享按钮 。 以升箭为矩.
At the bottom toolbar, there is a share button. It's a rectangle with an up arrow.
哦,没关系。 对
Oh, okay. Yeah.
对 如果你点击它, 它会给你选择 你想要分享的东西。
Yeah. If you click that, and it'll give you options of what you want to share.
对
Yeah.
所以我建议你分享一个 说整个屏幕或所有的东西或什么的
So I suggest you share the one that says whole screen or everything or something
像这样
like that.
摆
Okay.
上面说我不能分享 为什么?
It says that I'm not allowed to share. Why?
垛
Um.
我不知道.
I don't know.
上面说现在任何人都可以分享
It says that anybody can share right now.
上面写着,我想点击分享,但它没有给我这个选择。
It says, I want to click on share, but it doesn't give me that option.
它不允许我点击它。
It doesn't allow me to click it.
每个人都可以分享,对不对? 伊兹,你只是分享,所以...
Everybody else can share, right? Izzy, you just shared, so-
对
Yeah
维达,我不知道你那边怎么了
... Vida, I don't know what's going on on your side.
摆 但是,我可以只是... 好吧,我以后再学,但我不想慢一点
Okay. But can I just... Okay, I will learn this after, but I don't want to slow
你们
you.
摆
Okay.
这么说
So,
我的问题是 我在资产方面 然后...
just my question was, I was on the assets part, and then-
你是说在Blender?
In Blender, you mean?
对 我是在加钱。
Yeah. I was on the add-ons.
摆 让我回到我的... 让我分享我的Blender屏幕,
Okay. Let me go back to my... Let me share my Blender screen,
这样
so that
也许你可以让我通过它。
maybe you can walk me through it.
对 带我穿过它。
Yes. Walk me through it.
所以,你在这里,编辑 -
So you're here, Edit-
对
Yeah.
参考文献,添加,对不对?
References, Add-ons, right?
对
Yeah.
接着是MPFB.
And then MPFB.
单单 摆
Wait. Okay.
对吧?
Right?
还有所有 这就是你说的吗? 对
And all Is this what you're talking about? Yeah.
但我从哪里看到MPFB?
But where do I see MPFB?
喜欢... 你必须安装它。 如果你没有安装,它就不会出现
Like... You have to install it. If you haven't installed it, it won't show up
这里 哦,没关系。 所以我还是要安装它。 摆
there. Oh, okay. So I still have to install that. Okay.
对
Yeah.
摆
Okay.
Make Human有一个YouTube频道 介绍如何安装所有这些东西。
MakeHuman has a YouTube channel that shows you how to install all of these things.
所以,我们将离开你。 摆 如果你还在挣扎 请告诉我
So we'll leave you to that. Okay. And if you still struggle with it, do let me know
在Matimest, 我会帮你。 但与此同时,我要继续前进,好吗?
in Mattermost, I'll help you. But in the meantime, I'm going to move forward, okay?
对 摆 好吧,我们走。
Mm-hmm. Okay. All right.
所以,我们做的最后一件事,我们正在做 应用资产,库设置,装入
So the last thing we were doing, we were doing Apply Assets, Library Settings, Load
从 Zip 文件包装, 您应该选择 Make Human System 资产 zip
Pack from Zip File, and you should have selected the MakeHuman System Assets zip
要打开的文件,它应该安装在您的
file to open, which should have been installed in your
您创建的 MPFB 数据文件夹 。
MPFB data folder that you created.
这样我们就能把一个人变成人了 好吗?
With that done, we can now make somebody a human being. Okay?
所以,你要做的是让一个人去, 有一个叫做新人类的面板。
So what you do to make a human being is you go, there's a panel called New Human.
你点击它, 你会从头开始。
You click on that, and you're going to do it from scratch.
在这里你做了你的调整。 好吧,我要让这个互动。
And here you make your adjustments. All right, I'm going to make this interactive.
所以伊兹 告诉我 性别 中立 男性 还是女性
So Izzy, tell me, gender, neutral, male, or female?
中立. 中立. 摆 年龄,年幼,孩子,宝贝。
Neutral. Neutral. Okay. Age, young, child, baby.
单单 老,幼,孩子,还是婴儿? 宝贝 宝贝 摆
Wait. Old, young, child, or baby? Baby. Baby. Okay.
肌肉,最小,平均,最大吗?
Muscles, minimum, average, maximum?
最大一个。 最大肌肉宝贝。 摆 这会很有趣。
Maximum. Maximum muscle baby. Okay. This is going to be fun.
体重,最小,平均,最高?
Weight, minimum, average, maximum?
又是我吗?
Me again?
你说什么? 最少是别人 我尽量... 尽量 и琌程
What? Minimum- Someone else. I'll go maximum ... maximum. I'm maximum.
这将会是你的性格。 对
This is going to be your character. Yeah.
这是你的阿凡达 我们实时创作
This is your avatar right here we're creating in real time.
身高,矮,平均,高?
Height, short, average, tall?
平均数。 平均数。 摆 比例、反向V形状、平均值或
Average. Average. Okay. Proportion, inverted V shape, average, or
V形状? 颠倒V形. 颠倒V形.
V shape? Inverted V shape. Inverted V shape.
种族,世界,非洲,亚洲,高加索? 万国网. 万国网. 这是我的宝贝。
Race, universal, African, Asian, Caucasian? Universal. Universal. It's my baby.
好吧,我们走。 这里有乳房,大还是小? 小一点
All right. And here we have breasts, larger or smaller? Smaller.
小一点? 摆 乳房坚固,更坚固,更不坚固? 不太坚定。
Smaller? Okay. Breast firmness, more firm, less firm? Less firm.
我有点不舒服 问你这些问题, 但让我们前进。
I'm a little bit uncomfortable asking you these questions, but let's move forward.
摆 因此,这基本上就是一切。
Okay. So with that, that's basically everything.
顺便说一句 如果你出于什么原因 不喜欢你所做的选择
And by the way, if you for whatever reason didn't like the choices you made, there
是日后调整的方法。 因此,你只是做Create Human,和Voila,
are ways to adjust this later. So with that, you simply do Create Human, and voila,
你创造了一个,是什么?
you've created a, what was it again?
中性宝贝,最大肌肉... 这孩子对我来说太正常了 . . ....
Neutral baby, maximum muscle- The baby looks way too normal for me. ...
最大体重,平均身高。 对 所以这是... 对我来说太正常了
maximum weight, average height. Yeah. So this is- Looks way too normal for me.
我以为这些设置会很怪异
I thought it was going to be real freaky with those settings.
正如你注意到的 没有眼球 非常恐怖
And as you noticed, no eyeballs, very creepy.
但是,嘿,我们可以玩 这一点以后,好吗?
But hey, we can play with this some more later, okay?
因此,让我们给它一些眼球, 这就是资产变得非常
So with this, let's give it some eyeballs, and this is where the assets become very
帮助。 因此应用资产。 这次不是图书馆的设置,我们要去
helpful. So Apply Assets. This time, instead of Library Settings, we're going to go
先去皮肤 让我们给它一些皮肤。
to Skin first. Let's give it some skin.
抱歉,现在问问题可以吗?
Sorry, is that possible to ask a question now or not?
当然 来吧。
Yeah, sure. Go ahead.
我做了"Create Human" 但我还有魔方
I made a Create Human, but I still have the cube.
你想把立方体藏起来? 我也一样 我没有看到宝宝。
Oh, so you want to hide the cube? Same here. I don't see the baby.
怎么办?
How to do that?
单单 MakeHuman创造了一个立方体而不是婴儿?
Oh, wait. The Make Human created a cube instead of a baby?
我……
I
创造了一个你表现的人类 但我仍然有立方体
created a human just how you showed, but I still had the cube.
所以现在我看不到孩子了
So now I don't see the baby.
你想隐藏立方体。 你到右上角,然后...
You want to hide the cube. You go to the upper right-hand corner, and in the
然后点击眼球图标,它会
Outliner section, and find Cube, and then click on the eyeball icon, and it will
藏起来
hide it.
对
Mm-hmm.
在这里。 我的立方体还在
Up here. So, my cube is still there.
所以,如果我点击这里的眼睛, 我隐藏了立方体。
So if I click on eyeball here, I hide the cube.
摆 不错 我有宝宝。 对 非常感谢
Okay. Perfect. I have the baby. Yes. Thank you so much.
你在立方体里有个孩子 婴儿在盒子里。
You have a baby inside the cube. Baby in a box.
没错
It was.
对
Yeah.
我不知道为什么我的资产也没有装货 我以为我什么都有
I don't know why my assets are also not loading, and I thought I had everything
想到这里。
figured out here.
我有颜色吗? 哦,这可能是我的事情。 哦,我们走了。 好吧,我们走。
Am I getting color? Oh, it might be my thing. Oh, there we go. All right.
所以我就选了第一位非洲中年女性做配色
So I just picked the first one, middle-aged African female as the coloration, okay?
现在让我们做一些眼球。 摆
And now let's do some eyeballs. Okay.
在你增加眼睛之前,你需要加一个钻机,一个姿势
Before you can add eyes, you need to add a rig, a posing
内部机制。 因此,我们这样做之前, 我们去瑞金,我们去标准
mechanism inside. So before we do that, we go to Rigging, and we go to Standard
瑞格,我们只是说添加标准瑞格。
Rig, and we're going to just say Add Standard Rig.
你会看到这些线 出现在婴儿体内, 稍后,我会告诉你
And you'll see these lines appear inside the baby, and later on, I'll show you that
你可以用这个来移动孩子的姿势,好吗?
you can use this to move the baby's pose around, okay?
加上这台钻机,现在你可以回去加眼睛了.
With this rig added, now you can go back and add eyes.
原因是,眼睛需要去某处, 它需要去的结尾
The reason being, the eyes need to go somewhere, and it needs to go at the end of
这个拉杆,好吗? 所以,你要去应用资产,
this rigging stalk, okay? So you're going to go to Apply Assets,
眼睛图书馆,我不知道为什么 我的不出现, 但我要去做一个
Eye Library, and I don't know why mine is not showing up, but I'm going to do Add a
低保利眼,我点击这个。
Low Poly Eye, and I click that.
你看,现在他有眼球。 摆
And you see now he has eyeballs. Okay.
而现在她,他,我不确定, 但现在我们要去眉毛,我
And now she, he, I'm not sure, but then now we're going to go to Eyebrows, and I'm
要去添加眉毛一号。
going to add eyebrow number one.
摆 而子现在有眉毛. 好吗?
Okay. And the child now has eyebrows. Okay?
好吧,我们走。 如果你想操纵,
All right. And if you want to manipulate,
我想伊兹说这对她来说还不够激进 所以我们可以去
I think Izzy said that this is not radical enough for her, so we can go to the
在这儿建个小板块
Modeling subpanel here,
转到
and go to
外观型. 在Phenotype下,你可以在这里真正开始玩东西。
Phenotype. Under Phenotype, this is where you can start really playing with things.
所以,你可以玩 肌肉和体重 和所有其他的东西 你的心脏
So you can play with muscle and weight and all that other stuff to your heart's
内容。
content.
摆
Okay.
好吧,我们走。 所以我要离开它 这样,我要去回Solid
All right. So I'm going to leave it like that, and I'm going to go back to Solid
查看除色.
View and get rid of the colors.
在这里,我要告诉你为什么 我们花了第一个小时做我们所做的。
And here, I'm going to show you why we spent the first hour doing what we did.
摆 藏那些东西的钥匙
Okay. N key to hide all of that stuff.
这个婴儿是网状的,就像立方体一样
This baby is a mesh, just like the cube or the
其中 我们的性格或者我们刚做的香水瓶
Among Us character or the perfume bottle we just made.
所以,如果我点击Tab键进入编辑模式, 我得到我的顶点,好吗?
So if I hit the Tab key to go into edit mode, I get my vertex points, okay?
这么说
So,
比如,我不知道,让我们
for instance, I don't know, let's
给这个孩子一些刺。 我不知道我们为什么要这么做 但我要这么做
give this baby some spikes. I don't know why we would do that, but I'm going to do
无论如何 所以我要选那个顶点,按下Shift键,这个顶点,做这个
it anyway. So I'm going to select that vertex, hit Shift key, this vertex, do this
顶点,我会做G,Z。
vertex, and I'm going to do G, Z.
哦,我的计算机崩溃了,这就是原因。
Ooh, my computer is crashing, that's why.
按 G、Z 键。
G, Z.
好吧,所以我加 钉我的宝贝。 G, Z.
Okay, so I'm adding spikes to my baby. G, Z.
好吗?
Okay?
所以,现在婴儿与尖刺。
So now baby with spikes.
所以它可以被操纵, 例如,你想有一个更大的鼻子。
So it can be manipulated, and for instance, you want a bigger nose.
你可以进入编辑模式,可以尽量选择方块.
You can go into edit mode, and you can try your best to select the squares.
我们保留组成鼻子的方块。
We keep the squares that make up the nose.
这是网络操纵
This is mesh manipulation right here.
我们在玩这个角色的网格
We're playing with the mesh of this character.
我时间如何? 我还有20分钟
How am I doing on time? I still have 20 minutes.
好吧,我有一个鼻子, 我想把这家伙变成皮诺曹。
All right, so I've got a nose, and I want to turn this guy into Pinocchio.
我要做G移动,Y移动的方向, 我得到了皮诺曹。
I'm going to do G to move, and Y the direction to move, and I got Pinocchio.
摆
Okay.
因此,Make Blender Human是一个网格,可以像其他网格一样被操纵.
So the Make Blender Human is a mesh that can be manipulated like any other mesh.
好了,我现在就把那些东西都拆掉
Okay, I'm going to undo all of that stuff for now.
我要告诉你如何为这个孩子 快速做一件运动服,好吗?
And I'm going to show you how to make a bodysuit for this baby very quickly, okay?
所以,也许裸体宝宝不是那么好。 所以,我们要做的是,首先,我
So maybe naked baby is not so nice. So what we're going to do is, first of all, I'm
转弯... 回去这里
going to turn the... Go back here
转到Edit. 首先,我要把手臂藏起来
And go to Edit. First of all, I'm going to hide the armature.
所以在提纲里,我有个叫Human Rig的
So in Outliner, I have something called Human Rig.
我要打到眼球图标 来清除那些分散注意力的线条
I'm going to hit the eyeball icon to get rid of all those distracting lines.
编辑模式。 所以,让我们给这个孩子一件衬衫。 好吗?
Edit Mode. So let's give this baby a shirt. Okay?
所以,我要做的,像我以前一样, 是做X光模式,我要
So what I'm going to do, like I did before, is to do X-ray mode, and I'm going to
选择
select
婴儿的网状部分,像这样。 好吗?
some portion of the baby's mesh, like that. Okay?
所以我选择了网状的前后部分。
And so I select the front and back of the mesh.
我要做Shift+D, 就是重复我刚刚选择的。
And I'm going to do Shift+D, which is to duplicate that thing that I just selected.
哎哟
Oopsies.
哦,我只是做了一些可怕的事情。
Oops, I just did something horrible.
好吧,首先我想我需要锁定 这个婴儿的尺寸,控制+A,并应用
Okay, first I think I need to lock in the scale of this baby, Control+A, and apply
旋转和大小对婴儿。 返回这里并 Shift+D 到
rotation and scale to the baby. Go back to here and Shift+D to
重复 。 为什么它做疯狂的事情?
duplicate. Why is it doing crazy things?
对不起,我在想 到底什么是错在这里 我的宝贝。
Sorry, I'm trying to figure out what is messed up here with my baby.
应用?
Apply?
我现在要应用所有这些东西。
I'm going to apply all these things now.
应用手臂? 不,先躲起来 是吗?
Apply the armature? No, hide out first. Hmm.
让我们先复制整个婴儿。
Let's duplicate the whole baby first.
两个孩子 关闭X光模式 。 好吧,我要玩这个。
Two babies. Turn off X-ray mode. Okay, I'm going to play with this.
我觉得... 哦,这里。 这个宝贝撞上了Tab键.
I think... Oh, there. This baby and hit the Tab key.
前视,
Front view,
X射线 选择他身体的一部分。
X-ray. Select a portion of his body.
复制, Shift+D 要复制 。 哦,它做了这个奇怪的事情。
Duplicate, Shift+D to duplicate. Oh, it's doing this weird thing.
是吗?
Hmm.
摆 Blender正在做一些非常,非常奇怪的事情,我理解。
Okay. Blender's doing something very, very strange, I understand.
但无论如何,我会找出 发生了什么事,回到你身边
But anyway, I'm going to figure out what's going on here and come back to you
等会 但这里的要点是,我在选择 身体的区域是,
later. But the point here is that I'm selecting the area of the body that is
基本上什么是衬衫。 我会... 对不起 艾琳 来吧。
basically what would be a shirt. And I'm going to... Ah, sorry, Erin. Go ahead.
是的,我有一个问题。 当我尝试选择事物, 我仍然在眉毛,所以
Yeah, I have a question. When I try to select things, I'm still in the eyebrows, so
我只能选择
I can only select
和眉毛有关的东西
something which is related to the eyebrows.
我不知道如何取消选择 回到我的...
I don't know how to unselect to go back to my-
哦,没关系。
Oh, okay.
我猜你的眉毛和婴儿的身体不一样
So I guess the eyebrow for you is a different object than the body of the baby.
所以你只需要选择婴儿的身体。
So all you have to do is select the body of the baby.
对
Yes.
还是你...
Or you-
我不知道.
I don't know.
对 我不知道. 左边写着"用户视角"
Yeah. I don't know. On the left where it says User Perspective, for me, it says
人类的眉毛, 我不知道如何...
Human Eyebrow, and I don't know how to...
如果我试着选择...
If I try to select the-
对 我会...
Yeah. I'm going to...
还有14分钟 你共享屏幕。 见汝作么生.
14 minutes to go. You share screen. Let's see what you're doing.
你能看到我的屏幕吗?
Can you see my screen?
我能看到你的屏幕,是的。
I can see your screen, yes.
是啊,所以如果我尝试选择, 它只是停留在...
Yeah, so if I try to select, it just stays on-
啊,因为你选择了眉毛作为一个东西之后,就处于编辑模式了.
Ah, because you're in edit mode after having selected the eyebrow as a thing.
所以回去吧,Tab回到对象模式
So go back, Tab to go back to Object mode.
摆 对
Okay. Yep.
现在选择身体,而不是眉毛。
And now select the body, not the eyebrow.
是啊,现在它很好。
Yeah, now it's good.
不,不是臂部, 身体,网状是身体。 摆
No, not the armature, the body, the mesh that is the body. Okay.
对
Yeah.
现在再打Tab.
Now hit Tab again.
对
Yeah.
现在你可以选择身体。
And now you can select the body.
不错 谢谢
Perfect. Thank you.
摆 所以这里的关键是,谢谢你的做, 但这里的关键是什么
Okay. So the key here is, thank you for doing this, but the key here is whatever
在按下 Tab 键前选择的对象将进入编辑模式
object you select before you hit the Tab key to go into Edit mode will be the thing
在编辑模式中编辑。 其他的都无法编辑
that gets edited in Edit mode. And everything else is going to be non-editable and
不可选择。 好吗?
non-selectable. Okay?
对 谢谢
Yep. Thanks.
对 不用谢
Yeah. You're welcome.
你知道吗? 我要把操控和衬衫交给别人
You know what? I'm going to leave the manipulation and the shirt making to another
无论如何,会话。 所以还有谁想分享?
session anyway. So anybody else want to share?
蒂娜,你能给我看看你的生物吗,人类?
Tina, can you show me your creature, human?
这个嘛,我...
Well, I-
虚拟你
Virtual you.
谢谢你,让我们来看看。
Thank you so much, so let's see.
我刚刚开始,但我想我...
I just started, but I think I had...
因为你提到一些你必须拯救的东西,对不对?
Because you mentioned something about you have to save, right?
什么时候你把 资产包?
When you put in the asset pack?
或者下次我进去的时候 就会是... 瓳
Or next time I'll go in, it will be a... Oh.
不,不,不,你没事。 你很不错。
No, no, no, you're good. You're good.
我很好吗?
I'm good?
你唯一需要保存的就是偏好
The only thing that you needed to save was preferences.
所以,如果你去,帮我一个忙, 去编辑,优惠。
So if you go, do me a favor, go to Edit, Preferences.
对
Yeah.
而造众生. 摆 而你现在没有一条路 在那里它说路径
And Make Human. Okay. And you don't have a path right now where it says Path to
MPFB 用户数据. 中右侧. 对,继续往下走,往下走,往下走
MPFB User Data. Middle right side. Yeah, keep going down, down, down, down.
您没有定义文件夹 。
You don't have a folder defined there.
对
Yeah.
您需要设置一个路径到文件夹 。
You need to put a path to a folder there.
对
Yeah.
好吗? 在你把那个... 这是什么?
Okay? After you've put the... What's that?
路吗? 路径 --
Path here? Path to-
对
Yeah.
好吧,没错。
Okay, yeah.
到一个文件夹,在那里你收集你的所有资产和其他一切。
To a folder where you collect all your assets and everything else.
你需要这个在这里, 否则一切都会消失之后。
You need this to be here, or else everything will disappear after.
对
Yeah.
一旦你踏上你的路 在左下角
And then once you've set your path, on the lower left-hand corner, there are the
汉堡三刀图标,左下角 左下角头.
hamburger three-stripe icon, lower left-hand corner. Lower left-hand corner.
继续下去 是啊,点击这个, 然后你可以保存你的喜好。
Keep going down. Yeah, click on that, and then you can save your preferences.
好吧,超级。
Okay, super.
必须在您定义了您的用户数据文件夹后进行 。
That must be done after you've defined your user data folder.
对 我迷路了 当你早些时候说。
Yes. I got lost in that when you said that earlier.
别担心 这是...
No worries. This is-
对 当然
Yeah. Sure
...正是为什么我们要举行这个会议。
... precisely why we're having this session.
对
Mm-hmm.
好吧,不错。 所以你成功地创造了一个人类。
Okay, good. So you've successfully generated a human.
茱莉亚,你一直很安静 你对你的人类怎么样?
Julia, you've been very quiet. How are you doing with your human?
我觉得不错。 如果你想,我可以分享我的屏幕。
I think okay. I can share my screen, if you want to.
对
Yeah.
看起来像现在。
Looks like this right now.
哇,看看那个。 什么都是球吗? 是你吗?
Whoa, look at that. What are all the balls? Is that you?
我不知道. 对不起,这是德语。
I don't know. I'm sorry, it's in German.
所以我进入了编辑模式
So I went into Edit mode, and
我不知道他们为什么...
I don't know why they're-
啊,我想你选择了手臂。 所以这是武装操纵。
Ah, I think you selected the armature. So this is armature manipulation.
对
Right.
所以,继续打塔布回来。
So go ahead and hit Tab to go back out.
对
Yes.
或者回到Object模式 不管是德语还是德语
Or go back to Object mode, whatever that is in German.
对
Yeah.
对象模式 。 没错 选择皮肤而非内骨.
Object mode. Exactly. Select the skin, not the internal bones.
但选择您角色的皮肤 。
But select the skin of your character.
哪里? 哪里来的?
Where?
瓳
Oh,
不,说吧。 你做得对 选择
no, go ahead. You were doing it right. Select.
对 选择
Yeah. Select that.
开始了 这就是你的皮肤
There we go. So that's your skin.
对
Yeah.
现在点击 Tab 进入编辑模式 。
Now hit Tab to go into Edit mode.
摆
Okay.
现在你可以操纵...
And now you're able to manipulate...
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
现在,点击身体外。 点击
Right now, click outside the body. Click.
对
Yeah.
摆 使用拖曳选择, 我要你选择这个
Okay. Using a drag select, I want you to select this
手的一部分。 拖动左侧的手部。
portion of the hand. Drag select this portion of the hand on the left side there.
凉爽。 好吧,我们走。 现在我要你输入G键盘
Cool. All right. Now I want you to type G into your keyboard.
对
Yes.
摆 然后把你的手臂转过来。
Okay. And then move your arm around.
现在你可以重新定位,拉长,做各种事情。
Now you can reposition, lengthen, do all kinds of stuff.
所以这里的要点是 不要把你的人造物当作一个人物,而是想
So the point here is to not think of your human creation as a figure, but think of
它是一个网,你可以玩一整天。 好吗?
it as a mesh that you can play with all day long. Okay?
摆
Okay.
现在像这样点击,然后...
So now click that like that, and...
实际上,取消。 Control+Z 要撤销。
Actually, undo. Control+Z to undo.
对 当然
Yeah. Of course.
让我们确保你能... 你可以看到这一点。 我想选择一切。
Let's make sure you can... You can see that. I want to select everything.
你错过了后面的几个点 所以再选一次
You missed a few dots in the back. So do a selection one more time.
摆 让我们绕着你的身影旋转 确保一切都被选中了
Okay. Let's rotate around your figure to make sure everything was selected.
好吧,看起来不错。 现在,让我们做一个G, 伸长手臂给我。 或者让我们做...
Okay, that looks good. Now let's do a G, lengthen that arm for me. Or let's do...
对 哦,这就是骨头。 没关系 摆 手臂伸长并点击那里。
Yeah. Oh, that's the bones. That's fine. Okay. Lengthen the arm and click there.
好吧,不错。 然后点击Tab以返回对象模式.
Okay, good. And then hit Tab to go back to Object mode.
摆 然后,是的,所以现在你的人 有荒谬的长臂。 好吗?
Okay. And then, yeah, so now your person has ridiculously long arms. Okay?
摆
Okay.
很不错。
Very good.
但是骨头会正常的
But the bones will stay normal.
骨头暂时会正常的
The bones will stay normal for now.
摆
Okay.
对 好吧,所以如果你Control+Z, 你可以撤销 我们刚刚所做的可笑的事情
Yes. Okay, so if you Control+Z, you can undo the ridiculous thing that we just did
回到正常状态
to get back to normal.
谢谢
Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
艾琳 是的 问题
Erin, yes, question.
不,对不起,那还是从前的。
No, sorry, that was still from before.
啊,还好。
Ah, okay.
好吧,我们走。 我想我会... 其实,让我再给你看一件事
All right. I think I'm going to... Actually, let me just show you one more thing
在 -- -- 之前,
before-
我有个问题
I have a question.
对 说吧
Yeah. Yes, go ahead.
对 我是梅兰妮 我看不出属性上的修饰符
Yeah. Melanie speaking. I don't see the modifier in properties
选项卡。
tab.
正常吗?
Is it normal?
修改属性标签 。 好吧,你能分享你的屏幕吗?
Modifier properties tab. Okay, can you please share your screen?
所以我有两个屏幕 所以我尽力了
So I have two screens, so I do my best.
摆
Okay.
这里。
Here.
我不见修饰工具.
I don't see the modifier tool.
摆 你的屏幕是... 嗯,我没有,我可能看起来有点...
Ah. Your screen is... Well, I don't, I might seem a little...
哦,因为,好吧,这是非常好的。 这是一个伟大的问题。
Oh, because, okay, that's very good. This is a great question.
修改者
The modifier
工具,它的背景。 所以,现在,呃, 刚刚发生了什么?
tool, it's contextual. So right now, uh-uh, what just happened?
所以,现在,我认为你的骨头是被选中的, 所以你看到一个绿色的骨头
So currently, I think your bones are selected, so that's why you see a green bone
以及一个解除功能的字符,因为它认为你想为您的
and an armature character because it thinks you want to do settings for your
武装。 所以,继续点击你的人,就像我说的皮肤一样
armature. So go ahead and click on your human person, like a skin like I said
之前,我刚说
before.
这是我的屏幕。
This is my screen.
选择皮肤
Select the skin
就在这里。
right there.
你能看见我的标记吗? 对 人类,点击你的提纲中的人类一词.
Can you see my mark there? Yeah. Human, click on the word human in your outliner.
我是人类。 人类?
I'm on the human. Human?
不是人类的钻机,而是人类的下面。
Not human rig, but human below that.
抱歉,我有一个小屏幕和一个大屏幕,所以。
Sorry, I have a small screen and a big screen, so.
哇,真恶心
Whoa, funky.
哈罗,哈罗,哈罗。
Hello, hello, hello.
摆 所以我看不太清楚。
Okay. So I don't see really well.
不是这个屏幕 现身十亿遍. 坚持住。
Not this screen. We're seeing ourselves a billion times. Hold on.
我本来要跳支舞的
I was going to do a dance.
好吧,给我看看。 我停止分享。
Okay, show me. I stop sharing.
好吧,没事。 我会分享我的屏幕。
Okay, fine. I will share my screen.
所以我打开……
So I go to the
列表 -
list-
没有,没有。 坚持住。 坚持住。 请给我一点时间 给我一秒钟。
No, no. Hold on. Hold on. Just give me a second, please. Give me a second.
我给你看,这样你就不用猜了
I'm going to show you so that you don't have to guess.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧,我们走。 让我分享屏幕。
All right. Let me share screen.
好吧,我们回到婴儿, 我会确保我的人类钻机是能够
Okay, we're back on the baby, and I'm going to make sure my human rig is able to be
看见了 好吧,如果我选择钻机, 好吧,所以如果我选择钻机,你看
seen. Okay, and if I select the rig, okay, so if I select the rig, you see that
我的地产菜单跟你完全一样 对吧?
my properties menu looks exactly like yours, right?
对 对
Yes. Yes.
摆
Okay.
在 Human Rig 下方，有一个带黄色三角形图标、名为 Human 的类别。
Underneath human rig, there's a category called human with a yellow triangle.
如果您点击此选项, 属性菜单会更改为上下文
If you click on that, then the properties menu changes to be contextual to that
对象,现在有修改符。
object, and now you have modifier.
摆
Okay.
好吗? 所以这是很好的。 让我们玩这个。
Okay? So that's good. Let's play with that.
所以,如果我有修饰剂, 好吧,让我们做一些真正有趣的事情。 现在生成。
So if I have modifier, okay, let's do something really fun. Now generate.
我们该怎么办? 让我们做螺旋桨。
What should we do? Let's do corkscrew.
好吧,这会做可怕的事情 我的宝贝。
Okay, this is going to do horrible things to my baby.
好了,这里是修饰者的力量。
Okay, so here's where the power of modifiers.
我现在把我的孩子 编成艺术作品
I've now corkscrewed my baby into something like an artistic
雕塑,
sculpture,
或者我不知道这是不是艺术了。
or I don't know if this is art anymore.
好吧,我有一个奇怪的... 我现在对孩子做了可怕的事 好吗?
Okay, so I've got this weird... I've done horrible things to the baby now. Okay?
这是无损的。 就像我说的 如果我点击
And it is non-destructive. Like I said, if I click
X去掉那个修饰剂 他又回到了正常的婴儿状态
X to just delete that modifier, he goes back to being a normal baby.
但是修饰者是乐趣。 所以你可以进去,我们还能做什么? 三角ulate.
But modifiers are fun. So you can go in here and what else can we do? Triangulate.
哦,好吧,毁灭者。 所以,阿纳斯塔西已经显示 像一个低poly版本
Oh, okay, decimate. So, Anastasi had shown like a low-poly version
我不记得他的名字了
of figures by some artist, I can't remember the guy's name.
你可以去生成,毁灭, 然后比例现在是一个。
You could go generate, decimate, and then the ratio right now is one.
所以,如果我把这个非常低, 你可以看到婴儿变成一个几何形状。
So if I take this really low, you see the baby becomes like a geometric shape.
好吗? 这样你就可以玩了。 现在你有了外星宝贝
Okay? So you can play with that. So now you got alien baby,
几何异形婴儿.
geometric alien baby.
摆
Okay.
我还有一个问题
I have another question.
对
Yeah.
如果我想保持头部
If I want just to keep the head
使颈部平缓。
and to make the neck flat.
保持头部。 摆 好吧,我们走。
Just keep the head. Okay. All right.
所以,随着孩子的皮肤被选中,我打塔布去
So with the skin of the baby selected, I hit Tab to go to
编辑模式。 我要这样选择脑下的一切
edit mode. I'm going to select everything underneath the head like this.
确定全部选中. 哦,我没有X光视觉,所以它
Make sure it's all selected. Oh, I didn't have X-ray vision on, so that's why it
做了那个可怕的事情。 所以,打开X光, 我会选择所有下面
did that horrible thing. So turning on X-ray, I'm going to select everything below
颈部。 我要打X删除和面孔。 哎哟
the neck. I'm going to hit X to delete and faces. Oops.
它不会做到这一点。 为什么? 这对我来说太疯狂了
It won't do it. Why? This is doing very crazy things for me.
这是Blender Pro的新版本吗? 摆
Is this a new version of Blender Pro? Okay.
我认为现在的问题正在发生 我需要找出答案
The problem right now that I think is going on, and I need to figure out the answer
现在的这个"MakeHuman网"不是真的
to this, is that right now this MakeHuman mesh is not a true
网点。
mesh.
好吧,让我看看。 让我试试看
Okay, let me see. Let me try something.
是啊,你应该可以删除它的一部分, 但它没有工作。
Yeah, you should have been able to just delete a part of it, but it's not working.
我想我需要控制D,
And I think I need to Control D,
做第二个复制, 我想让我们尝试把这个转换成网状。
make a second copy, and I think let's try converting this to mesh.
转换成网状
Convert to mesh.
摆 摆 所以现在这不再是MakeHuman的物体了, 我希望是纯粹的网状。
Okay. Okay. So now this is no longer a MakeHuman object, but a pure mesh, I hope.
标签和删除
Tab and delete
脸 对 现在,我可以操纵它。 摆
faces. Yes. Now I can manipulate it. Okay.
我刚刚做的事
So what I just did there,
再来一次 首先,我给孩子做了一份拷贝
one more time. First, I made a copy of the baby,
这里的皮肤通过D班
the skin here by doing Shift D.
第二,我做了正确的鼠标点击 选择转换成网状。
The second thing I did was do right mouse click and choose convert to mesh.
我刚刚想做什么? 网络操纵。
What was I trying to do earlier? Mesh manipulation.
所以,现在如果我去标签,我可以... 我想做件衬衫
So now if I go to tab, I'm able to... I wanted to make a shirt.
这就是我之前想做的 所以,让我们为这个孩子做一件运动服。
That's what I was trying to do earlier. So let's make a bodysuit for this baby.
现在应该可以了 我要做这样的事情
That should work now. I'm going to do something like this.
好吧,我会做D班的复制,
Okay, I'm going to do Shift D to duplicate,
我会像这个那样放大一点
and I'm going to scale it slightly a little bit bigger like this.
哎哟 在取消选举之前,我要打P
Oops. Before deselecting it, I'm going to hit P
我要用松散的零件把它分开
to separate it, and I'm going to separate it by loose parts.
但是,这是非常先进的,我们在这里这样做。
But it's very advanced that we're doing here.
关机
Turning off the
放大然后回去 好吧,现在我有两个东西
zoom and going back. Okay, so now I actually have two objects.
宝宝在我手上
I have the baby
和婴儿的衬衫,你可以变成衣服。 好吗?
and a shirt of the baby that you can turn into clothing. Okay?
因此,举例来说,我可以给它一种不同的颜色。
So with this, for instance, I can give it a different color.
杀了这个,做个黑色潜水衣
Kill this, make this a black scuba diving suit,
放大一点
and scale it up a little bit.
好吧,所以我有一个皮肤紧紧的西装 现在,一个橡胶西装。
Okay, so I have a skin-tight suit now, a rubber suit.
G, (英语).
G,
十,我可以把它放在婴儿上面。
X. I can put it on top of the baby.
G, Y. G, Z (英语).
G, Y. G, Z.
好吧,还是太近了。 我要把它放大一点 使它成为一个
Okay, it's still too close. I'm going to scale it up a little bit more to make it a
有点大。 或者我们可以做的另外一件事是 增加一个修饰器 给它一些
little bit bigger. Or another thing we can do is add a modifier to give it some
厚度 。 。 所以去修饰者,添加修饰者,生成,
thickness. So go to modifier, add modifier, generate,
固化,通过操纵厚度,我可以给这件衬衫
solidify, and by manipulating thickness, I can give this shirt
厚度 。 。
thickness.
我有一件运动服 我不知道. 你看过电影《沙丘》吗?
And I have a bodysuit. I don't know. Did you see the movie Dune?
这看起来像
This looks like
哈科宁男爵和他的西装
Baron Harkonnen and his suit.
摆 总之,我八点了 无论时间如何 已经两个小时了
Okay. Anyway, it's 8:00 for me. Whatever it is time for you. It's been two hours.
怎么样? 希望不会太糟
How was that? Hopefully, it wasn't too bad.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
摆 如果你迷路,迷惑,有问题 超越今天,请放进去
Okay. If you are lost, confused, have questions beyond today, please drop them in
我将尽力回答他们
the Blender channel of Mattermost and I'll do my best to answer them.
如果我没记错的话 下载有问题
If I remember correctly, there was an issue with downloading
麦克的Blender。 安装MPFB加载有问题
Blender for Mac. There was an issue with installing the MPFB add-on
因为某种版本不兼容 和某人在一起
at all, with somebody due to some sort of version incompatibility.
第三个问题是什么? 还有第三个我不记得了
What was the third issue? There was a third one that I couldn't remember.
但无论如何,请体谅, 如果你不能前进 与MakeHuman为Blender,
But anyway, please kindly, if you cannot move forward with MakeHuman for Blender,
把Blender频道的问题给我 我尽量回答
drop me the questions in Blender, the Blender channel, and I'll try to answer.
摆
Okay.
这是很多。 我们做了很多两个小时, 但希望,你有点明白
That was a lot. We did a lot two hours in, but hopefully, you kind of understand
还有Blender软件的力量 我迫不及待想看看什么很酷
the power of the Blender software, and I can't wait to see what kinds of cool
你做的东西。 好吗?
things you make. All right?
谢谢
Thank you very much.
不用谢 好吧,我们走。 再见 边
You're welcome. All right. Bye bye. Good night.
再见。 谢谢
Bye. Thank you.
再见。
Ciao.
再见。 谢谢
Bye. Thank you very much.
Bye. Thanks.
对
Yeah.